美国狙击手
这里热得像个蒸笼
It's a fucking hotbox.
这里的土有股狗屎味
Man, the fucking dirt here tastes like dog shit.
- 说得好像你吃过一样  - 闭上你的臭嘴
- Oh, well, you'd know, wouldn't you?  - Shut the fuck up.
发现一青年男子 一边观察车队一边与人通话 完毕
I got a military-age male that's on a cell phone watching the convoy, over.
如果你认为他在汇报车队动向 你有权采取任何行动 你自己决定 完毕
If you think he's reporting troop movement, you have a green light. Your call. Over.
也许他只是打电话给他老妈
Maybe he's just calling his old lady.
他走了
He stepped off.
稍等 两百码外 一名妇女和一名孩子朝车队走去
Hold on. I got a woman and a kid, 200 yards out, moving towards the convoy.
女的手臂不动 好像夹着东西
Her arms aren't swinging. She's carrying something.
她拿出来一枚手榴弹
Yeah, she's got a grenade.
她把一枚反坦手榴弹交给了那个孩子
She's got an RKG Russian grenade she just handed to the kid.
你说一名妇女和一名孩子?
You say a woman and a kid?
- 你看到没有? 能确定吗?  - 不能 你知道交战规定 你自己决定
- You got eyes on this? Can you confirm?  - Negative. You know the R.O.E. Your call.
哥们 如果你弄错了他们就会开掉你 把你一脚踢回莱文沃思
Man, they fry you if you're wrong. They send your ass to Leavenworth.
你打中了
You got it.
回来!
Hey, get back here!
- 永远不要把你的枪丢到地上  - 遵命
- You don't ever leave your rifle in the dirt.  - Yes, sir.
儿子 刚才那枪不错 你很有天赋
That was a hell of a shot, son. You got a gift.
你以后会成为一个出色的猎人
You're gonna make a fine hunter someday.
在使徒行传中
Here in the Book of Acts,
保罗多次因为自己的信仰
several times, Paul stands in judgment
受到审判
for what he believes.
有时 我们都要那样做
And at times, we all have to do that.
我们没有站在他的立场
I mean, we don't see with his eyes,
所以不能理解他所作所为的神圣意义
so we don't know the glory of his plan.
展现在我们面前的生活就像那令人费解的镜像
Our lives unfold before us like puzzling reflections in a mirror.
- 你在做什么?  - 当我们升天之日...
- What are you doing?   - And on the day we rise...
便会清晰看到并且理解保罗所作所为的奥秘所在
we will see with clarity and understand the mystery of his ways.
一起祈祷吧
Let us pray.
这世界上有三种人...
There are three types of people in this world...
羊 狼和牧羊犬
Sheep, wolves, and sheepdogs.
现在 有些人认为邪恶是不存在的
Now, some people prefer to believe that evil doesn't exist in the world.
如果邪恶降临 他们都不知道如何保护自己
And if it ever darkened their doorstep, they wouldn't know how to protect themselves.
这些人就是羊
Those are the sheep.
然后掠食者出现了
And then you got predators.
他们使用暴力欺压弱者 他们就是狼
They use violence to prey on the weak. They're the wolves.
还有一种人 他们天生具有战斗力
And then there are those who've been blessed with the gift of aggression
和保护羊群的强烈本能
and the overpowering need to protect the flock.
这些人很稀有 并能与狼对抗
These men are the rare breed that live to confront the wolf.
他们就是牧羊犬
They are the sheepdog.
我们这个家不培养羊
Now, we're not raising any sheep in this family.
如果你们变成狼我就抽你们的屁股
And I will whup your ass if you turn into a wolf.
韦恩
Wayne.
但我们要保护自己
But we protect our own.
今后 如果有人要揍你
Now, if someone tries to fight you
或者欺负你弟弟 你们要自己解决
or tries to bully your little brother, you have my permission to finish it.
是那家伙找杰夫的麻烦
The guy was picking on Jeff.
- 是这样吗?  - 是的
- Is that true?  - Yes, sir. Yes, he was.
你们自己解决了吗?
Did you finish it?
那你们就知道自己是谁了
Well, then you know who you are.
知道你们的目标是什么了
You know your purpose.
克里斯・凯尔今晚骑的是一匹名叫"大小姐"的马
Chris Kyle is on the horse Big Mistress here this evening.
你没问题的
You're all right.
准备好了
Now, get ready.
很好
That's good.
今晚他要冲刺目前的最高分 86分
So, tonight, he needs to beat the leading score of 86.
杰夫 你哥好像又赢了
Hey, Jeff. Looks like your brother did it again.
克里斯・凯尔
Chris Kyle.
老兄 那里又不是没人 你还戴着皮带扣出来
Man, wasn't nobody there. You come out with a belt buckle.
- 你戴它干什么?  - 戴着它上床
- What are you supposed to do with it?  - Supposed to get laid with it.
我要戴着它 看看能不能引起萨拉的兴致
I'm gonna wear it and see if it puts Sarah in the mood.
见鬼 一场大风都能让萨拉兴致勃勃
Shit, a strong wind'll put Sarah in the mood.
他们是这么说的吗?
Oh, is that what they say?
老兄 你知道高中时候他们是怎么叫她的
Man, you know what they called her in high school.
- 好了 别说了  - 爱吸的萨拉...
- All right. Don't say it.  - Sarah sucks-a-lotta...
- 没听到我说什么吗?  - 见鬼 克里斯
- What'd I say?  - Shit, Chris.
该死的
Goddamn it.
- 花钱不少啊 那两个姑娘 这就是为什么...  - 别扯了
- That was bucking money, those two girls. And that's why...  - No.
他一直盯着她看 这就是为什么上次...
He kept looking... He had his eyes on her, and that's why, the last time...
- 你一会儿就知道它的威力了  - 好吧
- Wait till you see what this does.  - Yeah.
答案马上揭晓!
Let's find out!
嘿 宝贝 谁想和牛仔明星上床? 搞什么鬼?
Hey, baby. Who wants to fuck a rodeo star? What the fuck?
你不是说明天才回来
You said you wasn't coming home until tomorrow.
- 我说什么?  - 不 是我没有...
- I said what?  - No, I just didn't...
克里斯 放开他好吗? 他什么也没干!
Chris, just leave him alone, all right? He didn't do anything!
- 我什么都不知道 救命!  - 克里斯 放开他!
- I didn't know shit, man. Help!  - Chris, leave him alone!
混蛋克里斯 放开他! 该死的! 你怎么回事?
Fucking Chris, leave him alone! Goddamn it! What is wrong with you?
- 他什么也不知道 是吗?  - 他不知道? 你不知道什么?
- He didn't know, all right?  - Oh, he didn't know? What didn't you know?
- 把帽子还给我  - 给他帽子 宝贝
- Just give me my hat.  - Get his hat, baby.
他不知道什么? 你以为这些枪是谁的?
He didn't know what? Whose rifles did you think those were?
这些男人衣服都是她的吗? 这些你都不明白?
Those clothes, those men's clothes weren't hers? Is that what you didn't know?
你到底怎么回事?! 你不能这样见人就打!
What the fuck is wrong with you?! You don't have to fucking punch everyone!
带上你的帽子赶紧滚
Put that fucking hat on and get the fuck out.
你到底怎么回事?
What the fuck is wrong with you?
滚出去
Get out.
我不知道你想要我怎么样
You know what? I don't know what you expect from me.
你把我扔在这里 每个该死的周末都和你弟弟跑出去
You drag me out here and then you run off with your brother every damn weekend.
你觉得我为什么这么做?
Why do you think I did this?
我需要有人关注! 你不明白吗?
I do this to get attention! Don't you get that?
收拾你的的东西 滚出去
Get your stuff and get out.
好 去你的 我走
Fine. Fine. You know what? Fuck you. Fine.
你以为参加比赛你就是个牛仔了
You think you're a cowboy 'cause you rodeo.
你根本不是什么牛仔 你就是个脏兮兮的牧场工
You're not a cowboy. You're just a lousy ranch hand.
你就是个该死的混蛋
And you're a shitty fucking lay.
别说风凉话
Don't say it.
你们打算什么时候结婚?
When's the wedding?
我知道你的意思 但是...
I understand what you're saying, but...
要知道我们应该游遍全州
You know, we get to travel over the whole state.
每周末去不同的城市
Different city every weekend.
与野马和公牛为伴
Broncs and steers.
- 我不知道 也许她说得对  - 她说得对?
- I don't know. Maybe she's right, though.  - She's right?
她说对什么了? 她说得不对 老兄 我们就是牛仔
Right about what, Chris? She's not right, man. We're cowboys.
- 我们生活在梦想中  - 下面是一则特别报道
- We're living the dream.  - This is a special report.
美国驻坦桑尼亚达累斯萨拉姆使馆
Those explosions set to go off at the U.S. embassies
和肯尼亚内罗毕使馆发生连环爆炸
in Dar Es Salaam, Tanzania, and Nairobi, Kenya,
爆炸显然是某些人针对美国发动的战争行为
were clearly a part of someone's war against the United States.
两起爆炸工造成80多人丧命 1700多人受伤...
More than 80 dead, more than 1,700 injured in two bomb blasts today...
嘿 杰夫 快看
Hey, Jeff. Jeff. Hey.
- 距离250英里  - 快看
- 250 miles apart.  - Look at this.
目前尚不清楚我们的敌人是谁
It is still unclear at this hour who our enemy is.
不过很显然使馆是他们的袭击目标
Although the embassies were obviously the targets...
- 看看他们对我们做了什么  - 伤者不是美国公民
- Look what they did to us.  - And injured are not Americans.
仍有八名美国公民遇难 其中包括一名儿童 五名美国人失踪
Still, eight Americans, including one child, are dead, and five are still missing.
征兵站
- 你来自德州  - 是的 长官
- So, you're from Texas.  - Yes, sir.
- 你很爱国  - 是的 长官
- You're a patriot.  - Yes, sir.
- 你被他们惹毛了  - 我要为美国服役
- And you're pissed off.  - I'm looking to be of service.
- 你喜欢战斗?  - 是的 长官
- You like to fight?  - Yes, sir.
你喜欢战斗 好的 想不想见识一下精英战士?
You like to fight. Okay. Well... Why don't you meet the warrior elite?
- 海豹突击队  - 是的 海陆空全能
- SEALs.  - Yep. Sea, air, and land.
我水性不怎么好 长官
Well, I'm not much for the water, sir.
不好? 我们这里不欢迎胆小鬼 多数人都被淘汰或主动退出了
No? Well, this ain't for the faint-a heart. Most men, they wash out, they quit.
长官 我不是多数人 我绝不言弃
But I'm not most men, sir. I don't quit.
- 要来点正经的了 伙计们!  - 坚持住! 姑娘们! 坚持住!
- This is where the fun stops, guys!  - Take it, girls! Take it!
就这样 姑娘们 坚持住 第一次都会疼
That's it, girls. Take it. Take it. Only hurts the first time.
- 看看这家伙 你要放弃了吧 小子?  - 报告罗勒指导员 绝不言弃
- What we got here? You a quitter, boy?  - Hooyah, no, Instructor Rolle.
放屁! 再让我看到你的屁股我就把它踢开花!
Bullshit! Yo ass is fleet meat if I ever did see it!
头转过来 小子 看着我 尝尝这滋味
Don't turn away from me, son. You look at me and you take this shit.
- 是 长官!  - 该死 你这个老混蛋!
- Hooyah, sir!  - Damn, you old as fuck!
你加入海军是因为在诺亚方舟里面待得太舒服了吧?
You join the Navy'cause you had such a good goddamn time on Noah's ark?
- 小子 你多大了?  - 报告 30岁!
- How old are you, boy?  - Hooyah, 30!
30岁? 你能给这里一半的人当爹了
30? Your fart dust could have fathered half these boys.
我们要淘汰废物
We gonna weed through the quitters.
我们今天要选出来一两位勇士
Yeah, we gonna find us a goddamn warrior or two today.
道博 你真的是从康涅狄格州来的吗?
Dauber, are you sure you're from Connecticut?
我是第一次见到来自哈特福特的乡巴佬
I ain't never met no hick from Hartford before.
报告弗莱德指导员 农村也是美国的一部分 我来这里是为了干掉恐怖分子的
Hooyah, Instructor Friday! Country's countrywide. I came here to kill terrorists.
谁告诉你可以傻笑的?
Who the fuck told your ass to giggle?
报告罗勒指导员 没有人!
Hooyah, no one, Instructor Rolle!
- 我允许你张嘴说话了吗?  - 报告罗勒指导员 没有
- Did I ask you to open up your mouth?  - Hooyah, no, Instructor Rolle.
看看你这一身肥肉 笑个屁
Look at your fat, pasty, giggly ass.
该死的! 你就是个喝可乐吃奇多的蠢货
Damn, son! You a big Dr. Pepper, cheeto-eating motherfucker.
这就是我想说的
Yeah. That's what I'm talking about.
比格斯 以后这就是你的名字 也是你回家的车票
Biggles. That's your name from now on, sunshine. And that's your ticket home.
D! 你还留在这里做什么? 想要加入我的队伍吗?
"D"! What are you still doing in my line, trying to make this team?
- 众所周知黑人不会游泳  - 没关系的 长官 我不是那样的黑人
- Everybody knows black guys don't swim. - It's all right, sir. I'm not black.
- 不是?  - 不是 我是新一代的黑人
- No?  - No. I'm the new black.
我们跑得慢 跳不高 会游泳 在Gap店里买衣服
We run slow, we jump low, we swim good, and we shop at Gap.
我让白人感到骄傲 我能拐走他们的女人 干翻她们!
And I make the white folk proud when I hose down their ladies. I dick 'em down!
加油!
Hooyah!
看那边! 有人退出了
There it is! That is a quitter.
你说你要走 我说走得好
You say goodbye, I say good riddance.
他现在半途而废 到了战场一样坚持不下去
He quits on you here, he's gonna quit in the field of battle.
形势紧张了 他都不会站出来 你中弹了 他也不会把你拖走
When shit gets hairy, he won't step up. Your ass gets shot, he won't pull you out.
我要的是战士!
I'm looking for warriors!
- 七!  - 继续数!
- Seven!  - Keep counting!
- 八! 九!  - 大声点!
- Eight! Nine!  - I can't hear you!
老家伙 你想让我给你妈咪打电话吗? 没准她做得都比你好
You want me to call your mama, old man? Maybe she could come and take your place.
这是前戏! 我再放点马文・盖伊的歌让你们好好干!
This is foreplay! I'm about to turn on some Marvin Gaye and get in that ass!
这就对了!
That's what I'm talking about!
小兵们 你们的蛋蛋在哪里?
Squirrel, Squirrel, Squirrel, where the fuck are your nuts?
长官 他们不在了 缩回去了
Oh, they're gone for good, sir. They crawled back up inside.
但他们很温暖
But they are warm.
小鬼讲大话!
Big talk from a little man!
你怎么样 老家伙?
Now you. How about you, old man?
感觉如何?
How you feeling?
报告 我觉得很危险
Hooyah, dangerous. Feeling dangerous.
大家听着 凯尔感觉到危险了
Hooyah! Kyle's feeling dangerous.
行动!
Move!
坐下来!
Take seats!
见鬼! 56度角 如此清新 如此干净
Damn! 56 degrees, so fresh, so clean.
再过几个小时 你们就是海豹突击队员了!
Only a few more hours, and you're Navy Seals!
- 我是唯一打中的 所以...  - 好吧
- I'm the only one who's hit one, so...  - Yeah.
轰!
Boom!
- 太棒了  - 克里斯 该你了
- Oh, yeah.  - Chris, your turn, man.
- 不 你再来一次吧  - 我再来一次? 好吧
- No, you got one more.  - I got one more? All right.
好 再一次 来吧
All right. One more. Here we go. Here we go.
我们需要个小点的靶子 老兄 我们用一下你的胳膊吧
Hey, we want a smaller target, we'll use your arm, man.
- 你好  - 嗨
- Hello.  - Hi.
你好吗?
How you doing?
不错 谢谢
Good. Thank you.
我能... 请你喝一杯吗?
Can I... get you a drink?
一杯酒能让你看起来更加高大有魅力?
Will a drink make you six inches taller and charming?
- 它能让你变回未婚状态?  - 我没有结婚...
- Will it make you not married?  - I'm not...
好吧 我刚才看见你把婚戒摘了 好吗?
Yeah. I just watched you take your ring off, okay?
别当无赖 回家吧
Don't be a scumbag. Go home.
天啊
Oh, my God.
- 可能是因为你穿了皮裤吧  - 是吗?
- It may have been the leather pants.  - Oh, yeah?
姑娘穿什么样的裤子才能不被骚扰呢?
What kind of pants does a girl have to wear to be left alone?
灯芯绒裤吧
Well, maybe corduroy.
你们这群人就是这样吗?
I mean, is that how it is with you guys?
你们三杯酒下肚 就成单身汉了?
You're, like, suddenly single after three beers?
不 三杯酒下肚 我就想要第四杯
Oh, no. After three beers, all I know is to get a fourth.
很好 标准农民作风
Oh, that's great. That's great. Real redneck.
我不是农民 我来自德州
Oh, I'm not a redneck. I'm from Texas.
有什么区别吗?
What's the difference?
我们骑马 它们一家人互骑
Well, we ride horses and they ride their cousins.
你是做什么的? 显然你是个军人
What do you do for work? You're obviously military.
我是给海豚洗澡的 圈养的海豚
I polish dolphins. They're in captivity.
我只是把它们身上的脏东西擦掉
What I do is just sort of scrape off the crustaceans.
- 你觉得我很蠢吗?  - 不 说实话 你看起来不太开心
- Do I look stupid to you?  - No. Honestly, you look a little sad.
- 我... 我的身高可以请你喝一杯吗?  - 你得先告诉我你是做什么的
- Am I... tall enough to buy you a drink?  - Not until you tell me what you do.
好吧 这样如何? 嘿 格雷格
Okay. How about this? Hey, Greg?
给我两个杯子 一杯酒一个问题怎么样?
Get two shots. How 'bout we do a shot for a question?
你每问我一个问题 我回答完 你要喝一杯酒 反过来也一样
Every time you ask me a question and I answer, you got to do a shot. Same, vice versa.
游戏开始
Game on.
这瓶酒就留在这吧 好 问吧
You can leave the bottle, too. Okay, shoot.
显然你是个军人 哪个部队的?
All right. You're obviously military. What branch?
我刚结束体能训练 马上要去狙击培训学校
I just finished BUD/S, heading to sniper school.
- 真的? 你是海豹突击队的?  - 没错
- Are you kidding me? You're a SEAL?  - Yes, ma'am.
- 这是第二个问题了  - 该死
- That's two questions.  - Shit.
真的?
Really?
哦 你没必要真喝掉的
Oh, I didn't really mean you had to do that.
好吧 该死
Okay. Shit.
我知道你们这些人 我妹妹以前和一个海豹陆战队员订过婚
I know all about you guys. My sister was engaged to a SEAL.
- 真的?  - 没错
- Oh, was she?  - Yeah.
等等 什么叫你知道我们这些人? 你想说什么?
Hold on. How you know all about us? What do you mean?
我想说你们是一群自命不凡 自我为中心的混蛋
What I mean is, you're a bunch of arrogant, self-centered pricks who think you can lie
你们劈腿 为所欲为 我绝对不会和一个海豹陆战队员约会的
and cheat and do whatever the fuck you want. I'd never date a SEAL.
等等 你为什么说我以自我为中心? 我能为我的国家献出生命
Wait. Why would you say I'm self-centered? I'd lay down my life for my country.
为什么?
Why?
因为这是世界上最伟大的国家 我要尽全力保护它
'Cause it's the greatest country on earth, and I'd do everything I can to protect it.
听着 我很遗憾你妹妹遇人不淑 但我不是那样的人
Look, I'm sorry what happened to your sister, but that's not me.
- 很高兴认识你  - 你要去哪里?
- It's nice to meet you.  - Where are you going?
回家 你说你不会和一个海豹突击队员谈恋爱 所以...
Well, I was just gonna go home because you said you wouldn't date a SEAL, so...
我只是说我从没嫁过罢了
I said I'd never marry one.
好吧 那么 也许... 你好 很高兴认识你 你叫什么名字?
Oh, okay. Well, then maybe, hello. Nice to meet you. What's your name?
- 塔雅  - 塔雅
- Taya.  - Taya.
我叫克里斯・凯尔 很高兴认识你 荣幸之至
Chris. I'm Chris Kyle. Nice to meet you. Pleasure.
你认为你能保护我们所有人 这有点自大 不是吗?
I mean, it's pretty egotistical of you to think you can protect us all. Isn't it, Chris?
好吧 我们体能指挥官说有三样...
Well, our BUD/S officer commander said that it's three...
他说有三样东西我们必须当心 自大 酒和女人
Okay. He said there's three things we got to worry about: Ego, booze, and women.
好吧 听起来你有危险了
Well, sounds like you're under attack.
你很漂亮
You're pretty.
你很可爱
You're so cute.
我帮你
I got you.
我不会跟你回家的 想都别想
I'm not going home with you, so don't even think about it.
感觉身体里的每个细胞都在呼吸
Feel breath filling every cell in your body.
这是我们的仪式
This is our ritual.
当我们掌控自己的呼吸 掌控自己的思想时
We master our breath, we master our mind.
扣动扳机甚至不需要意识
Pulling the trigger will become an unconscious effort.
你会感觉到 但不要去指挥它
You will be aware of it, but not directing it.
呼气时 找到你自然产生的呼吸间歇
And as you exhale, find your natural respiratory pause
和心跳间的停顿
and the space between heartbeats.
你好 我是塔雅 我不方便接电话 请留言 我会尽快回电
Hey. This is Taya. I can't get to the phone. Leave a message. I'll call you back.
嗨 又是我 那个被你吐了一鞋的人
Hey, it's me again. The guy whose shoes you puked on.
那个... 我想你可能没收到我的上一条留言
So... yeah, I was thinking maybe you didn't get that last message,
我留的那条 或者... 再上一条 所以我想...
the last message I left, or... the one before that. So I figured that...
- 你想怎么?  - 嗨 你好吗? 一切都好吗?
- You figured what?  - Hey. How are you? How've you been?
还不错
Good.
那就好 嗯 你在做什么?
Good. Wow. What are you up to?
什么也没做 你呢?
Not a lot. You?
我也没 就是... 很高兴能跟你说话
No, just... excited to talk to you.
瞄准物小 失误也小
Aim small, miss small.
如果你瞄准一粒衬衫纽扣 你可能会打偏两英寸
If you aim for a shirt button, you might miss by 2 inches.
但如果你瞄准他的衬衫 那你可能打偏两英尺
If you aim for his shirt, you might miss by 2 feet.
- 你最好把弹着点收紧 凯尔  - 是 长官
- You better close those groupings, Kyle.  - Yes, sir.
天啊
God.
- 不错 这样我们能赢到什么?  - 上面一排的
- Not bad. What do we get for that?  - Top shelf.
- 我喜欢那一个 棕色的那个  - 当然 拿着
- I like that one. Brown one.  - Sure. Here you go.
- 太好了 谢谢你 先生 祝你愉快  - 看呀! 谢谢
- Great. Thank you, sir. Have a good day. - Oh, look! Thank you.
- 你好  - 噢 很好 你抱着它很好看
- Hello.  - Oh, good. That looks good on you.
你一直都想做个军人吗?
So, did you always want to be a soldier?
不 我过去想当个牛仔 但是...
No. I wanted to be a cowboy, but...
我也不清楚 我做到了 然后就打算做点别的
I don't know. I did that. Thought I was meant for something more.
所以你就开始在酒吧里拯救女孩子了?
So you started rescuing girls from bars?
我想我是在你手里救出了那间酒吧
I think I rescued that bar from you.
- 你喜欢乡村音乐吗?  - 只有在消沉的时候才喜欢
- You like country music?  - Only when I'm depressed.
- 那孩子呢? 你想要孩子嘛?  - 是啊 将来某一天吧
- How about kids? You want kids?  - Yeah, someday.
我妈妈说看我的鼻子就知道我会选错男人
My mom says I have a nose for picking the wrong men.
这话对女孩说太糟糕了
Well, that's a shitty thing to say to a girl.
我已经证明了她是对的
Well, I've proven her right.
那就是错误的选择让你站在这里
Then wrong picks put you here,
让你变成现在的自己 我喜欢这样的你
made you who you are. I like who you are.
你想过如果那支枪的对面站的是一个真人会怎样吗?
You ever think about what happens when there's a real person on the end of that gun?
我不知道 我只希望当那一天到来时我可以胜任我的工作
I don't know. I just hope I can do my job when that day comes.
我们是在盯着同一个目标吗? 你根本就是在打沙子
Are we looking at the same target? You're spitting dust.
不过别担心 我们总是能用医护兵替下那些不能射击的人
And don't worry. We can always use corpsmen for the guys who can't shoot.
噢 该死
Oh, fuck.
- 你在发抖  - 我知道
- You're trembling.  - I know it.
- 如果你不想我们可以不这样做...  - 不 我想 真的
- We don't have to do this if you don't...  - No, I want to. I do.
- 是吗?  - 你这么的真实 这让我很害怕
- Yeah?  - You just feel real and it scares me.
你是闭着眼射的吗?
You got your off-eye shut?
如果我闭上眼 我就什么也看不见了
Well, if I close my off-eye, then I can't see what's out there.
- 那里除了靶子什么都没有  - 不 长官 那里有东西
- There's nothing out there but the target.  - Negative. Sir, there is something out there.
那就击中它
Punch it.
俯卧撑有用吗? 做50个 凯尔 注意安全
Will push-ups help? Give me 50, Kyle. Clear and safe.
当它呼吸时我发挥得更好
I'm better when it's breathing.
- 这时另一架...  - 天啊 克里斯!
- what appears to be another...  - Oh, my God. Chris!
- 怎么了?  - 不!
- What's wrong?  - No!
以下是视频资料 你可以看见第一架飞机似乎是从东面飞来
Here's the tape. You see the first plane coming in from what looks like the east side.
它冒着火冲进了大厦
And it goes into the building with the flames
从大厦另一端冒出了浓烟
and the smoke billowing out the other side of the tower.
我很难说准哪一面是北边 哪一面是南边
It's hard for me to tell exactly which is the north side and which is the south side.
但看起来烟是从大厦北面冒出
But it appears it's coming out of the north side there.
继而 不久之前 就发生了这惊人的一幕
And then, moments ago, these incredible images.
这应该是第一次 大厦南塔倒塌了
I believe that's the first one. That's the south tower collapsing.
这看起来像你见过的大厦爆破
It almost looks like one of those implosions of buildings that you see,
但这不是可控的爆破 这是一场大破坏
except there is nothing controlled about this. This is devastation.
你甚至都不了解我
You don't even know me.
我了解你够多了 你很完美 宝贝
I know enough. You are a package deal, babe.
- 你在害怕什么?  - 没什么
- What are you so afraid of?  - Nothing.
每件事都让我害怕 我也不知道 如果我们成不了怎么办?
Everything. I don't know. What if it doesn't work out?
我们会结婚 然后会组建一个家庭
We're gonna get married and then we're gonna start a family.
你都计划好了 是不是?
You got it all planned out, don't you?
没错
I'm done.
我爱你
I love you.
如果你语气这么坚定 那你需要一枚戒指哦
Well, you're gonna need a ring if you want to talk all tough like that.
好的
Okay.
女士们 先生们 有请克里斯・凯尔夫妇!
Ladies and gentlemen, Mr. and Mrs. Chris Kyle!
你脖子上是什么玩意?
What the hell is on your neck?
你的脖子 上面好像沾了些绿油漆
Your neck. You've got, like, green paint all over you.
你会相信吗 宝贝 如果我告诉你我刚刚做了静脉注射
Would you believe me, babe, if I told you I had an I.V.
我两小时之前全身都是绿色的
and I was all green about two hours ago?
你... 你说什么?
What are you... what?
- 这是我的一部分 宝贝  - 天啊
- It's a package deal, babe.  - Oh, my God.
给我过来
Come here, you.
谢谢
Cheers to that.
什么事 长官?
What's the word, chief?
刚刚接到命令 伙计们 开始了!
Just got the call, boys. It's on!
噢耶!
Hooyah!
干杯!
Shots!
很好!
Yes!
五杯
Five shots.
太好了!
Yeah!
- 只有六个星期 宝贝  - 我很害怕 宝贝
- It's only gonna be six weeks, baby.  - I'm so afraid, baby.
那应该是敌人说的 你没什么好怕的
That's what they say. You got nothing to be afraid of.
- 你在说...  - 这都是计划的一部分
- What are you...  - It's all part of the plan.
你的心脏都快蹦出来了
Your heart is beating out of your chest.
这只是因为不是一个人去参加战争 仅此而已
That's just 'cause I'm not the only one that's going to war. That's all.
干杯!
Cheers!
第一次海外部署
欢迎来到费卢杰 古老中东的新狂野西部
Welcome to Fallujah. The new wild west of the old Middle East.
基地组织已经悬赏你们的人头 现在世界各地的
AQI put a price on your heads, and now extremists from around the globe
极端分子都汹涌而来想要你们的命 狙击手们...
are flooding the borders to collect on it. You snipers...
你们每人会被分配一名海军陆战队员保护你们进入主路
you're gonna be paired with a marine to watch your back and inserted along the main road
掩护第一批海陆队员进行上门搜查
to do overwatch for 1st marines going door to door.
你们的工作是不惜一切代价保护好那些队员
Your job is to protect those marines at all costs.
城市已经被疏散
This city has been evacuated.
任何一个还待在这里的已到参军年龄的男子... 都是要来杀你们的
Any military-age male who is still here... is here to kill you.
我们要安全把逮捕这些 然后平安地回家
Let's bring these boys in safe and get our asses back home.
下 下 下!
Out, out, out!
最好把头低下 德州男
I'd keep that head down, Tex.
伊军也有狙击手的 你知道的
Muj got snipers, too, you know.
狙击手不会瞄你的头的
A sniper won't aim for your head.
伙计 他们有个从500码外就可以爆头的狙击手
Man, they got this one sniper that's been hitting head shots from 500 yards out.
他们叫他穆斯塔法
They call him Mustafa.
他还参加过奥运会
He's in the Olympics.
奥运会现在还有狙击这个项目?
They got sniping in the Olympics now?
稍等 两百码外 一名妇女和一名孩子朝车队走去
Hold on. I got a woman and a kid, 200 yards out, moving towards the convoy.
女的手臂不动 好像夹着东西
Her arms aren't swinging. She's carrying something.
她拿出来一枚手榴弹 她把一枚反坦手榴弹交给了那个孩子
She's got a grenade. She's got an RKG Russian grenade she just handed to the kid.
你说一名妇女和一名孩子?
You say a woman and a kid?
- 你看到没有? 能确定吗?  - 不能 你知道交战规定 你自己决定
- You got eyes on this? Can you confirm?  - Negative. You know the R.O.E. Your call.
哥们 如果你弄错了他们就会开掉你 把你一脚踢回莱文沃思
Man, they fry you if you're wrong. They send your ass to Leavenworth.
我靠 太牛掰了
Fuck, that was gnarly.
这个邪恶的婊子
Fucking evil bitch.
起来 继续前进
Get up. Keep moving.
- 射得好 德州男 真神了  - 收到 干得漂亮 海军
- Nice shooting, Tex. Hell of a call.  - Roger that. Good looking out, Navy.
- 你听到了吗 哥们?  - 别碰我
- Fuck, did you hear that, man?  - Get the fuck off me.
其他人呢?
Where is everybody?
我们在休整 我们在训练那些该死的哈吉士兵
We're just checking our dicks here, man. We're training those fucking Hajji soldiers.
是吗 那你为什么不去呢?
Yeah, why aren't you out there?
- 我有事  - 什么事 看漫画书?
- Well, I have the shits.  - What, reading a comic book?
这明明是漫画小说 伙计 跟漫画区别大了
It's a fucking graphic novel, man. There's a big difference.
我听说你在外面开枪了
I heard you were on fucking fire out there.
马克・李进来了 说你完成了你的首杀 是吗?
Marc Lee came in, said you popped your cherry. Is that right?
是个孩子... 他连毛都没长齐
There was a kid who... barely had any hair on his balls.
他妈妈给了他一枚榴弹
Mother gives him a grenade,
派他去炸海军陆战队
sends him out there to kill marines.
老兄 我从没见过这么恶毒的事情
Dude, that's evil like I never seen before.
是的 但是 听着哥们
Yeah. But, hey, man,
你知道那个孩子可能会杀掉十个海陆队员 对吧?
you know that kid could have taken out like 10 fucking marines, right?
是的 但我把他杀了
Yeah, but I killed him.
你只是尽了你的职责 这就足够了
You did your job. That's the end of the story.
是啊 只是这跟我想象中的首杀不一样
Yeah, it's just not how I envisioned that first one to go down.
莱利 没关系 没实际看到
Riley, it's okay. Don't have the actuals.
我靠! 什么玩意?
Fuck, man! What the hell?
那是你的掩护 爱因斯坦 你可以待会再谢他
That was your overwatch, Einstein. You can thank him later.
行动!
Let's move!
继续前进
Keep going.
加快速度
Hurry up.
散开@
Disperse!
停火! 停火!
Cease fire! Cease fire!
注意屋顶! 紧盯那里!
Eyes on the rooftop! Keep your eyes up there!
有人倒地! 有人倒地! 我们这里需要医护人员!
Man down! Man down! We need a corpsman over here now!
发现敌军狙击手 大致方位
Enemy sniper located. Approximate grid, Quebec-Romeo,
为QR155604
1-5-5-6-0-4.
- 闻起来像尿一样  - 是啊...
- Smells like piss in here.  - Yeah, well...
你成功掩护了我们 伙计 那几枪真漂亮
You covered our asses out there, man. Some ballsy shots.
- 靠 他们手里没武器是吧?  - 是的
- Fuck. They were clean, right?  - Hell yeah, they were.
那个该死的狙击手竟敢动手!
That fucking sniper went right up our ass!
是啊 不过我审问出这里的防御细节 不会再发生这种事了
Yeah, I already chewed out security detail. It ain't gonna happen again.
最好不要再发生了
It better not happen again.
- 四百米外有个热点  - 好吧
- There's a hot spot 400 meters out.  - All right.
我要去写狙击手陈述
I'm gonna go write up some shooter statements.
- 你干掉了几个人?  - 六个... 噢 不对 我说错了
- How many'd you get?  - I got six... oh. No, that's not true.
我干掉八个 但他们拿掉了两个
I got eight, but they dragged two off.
- 你射杀了六个?  - 是啊 怎么了? 有什么问题?
- You got six?  - Yeah. Why? What's wrong?
没什么 你比其他狙击手加在一起干掉的都多
Nothing. You just got more than the rest of the snipers combined.
- 是 但是他们也杀了我们一个  - 你总不能射杀你看不到的人
- Yeah, but they got one of us.  - You can't shoot what you can't see.
他妻子说他拿着一本可兰经
His wife said he was carrying a Koran.
听着 我不知道可兰经长什么样 但是我可以告诉你他拿着什么
Look, I don't know what a Koran looks like, but I can tell you what he was carrying.
那是个压型金属 弹型7.26s
It was pressed metal, shot 7.62s,
它看起来就像一把AK-47 你说他拿的是什么
and it looked just like an AK-47. So you tell me what he was carrying.
噢 他来了 他来了
Oh, here he comes. Here he comes.
女士们先生们 听我说! 我们之中诞生了一个传奇人物!
Ladies and genitals, listen up! We have a legend in our midst!
让我们以热烈的掌声欢迎"传奇"!
Round of applause for The Legend!
就是这样 我们为你的凯旋而感到骄傲 小伙子
There we go. We're so proud of you back home on the range, boy.
据说... 据说这个传奇人物
Now, it's been... it's been said that The Legend here
可以一口气杀死一百个人
can kill 100 men with one blow.
或者 不 应该是... 什么是... 不 应该是...靠 是什么来着?
Or, no, it was... what was... nah, it was... fuck. What was it?
是...是每人吹一次...他吹了一百个...男人
It was one... one blow from a single man. He blew 100... men.
他还是单身 而且...我去! 真是的!
And he's single. And... Goddamn it! Shit!
噢 天啊!
Oh, shit!
- 你妹  - 该死
- Damn, man.  - Oh, fuck.
你想来场食物大战吗? 来啊
You want a food fight? Come on.
- 讨厌  - 这是让你闭嘴的唯一方式
- Shit.  - Only way to shut you up.
你杀人了吗?
Have you killed anyone yet?
这可不应该是打电话该聊的啊 宝贝
That is not the way the call home is supposed to go, babe.
别跟我开玩笑 说真的 我想让你告诉我一切
Don't be weird with me. Seriously. I want you to tell me everything.
呃 有些事情是不能通过电话说的
Well, there's certain things you just can't say over the phone.
听着 是你把我吵醒的 是吧?
Okay, you knocked me up, right?
我自己坐在这里组装宝宝床
And I'm sitting here by myself literally assembling baby cribs,
可你却什么也不能跟我说? 这就是你的宏大计划?
and you can't talk to me? That's your big plan?
你们在那边基本搞定了吧?
You guys almost done over there yet?
我总是不住的想你在蜜月时穿的粉红色小衣服
I can't stop thinking about that little pink number you wore on our honeymoon.
是啊 那叫睡衣
Yeah, it's called a nightgown.
对
Yeah.
而且三天...
And three days...
三天不能叫做蜜月
three days is not a honeymoon.
那三天非常愉快
Well, it was a good three days.
我真的很想你
I miss you real bad.
我也想你
I miss you, too.
- 喂 你想我跟你说点下流的话吗?  - 想
- Hey, you want me to talk dirty to you?  - Yeah.
等等 等等 我得...
Hold on. Hold on a second. Let me just...
我... 一手拿着电话一手拿着枪
I got... a phone in one hand and a gun in the other,
我不知道应该做什么
so I don't know what I'm gonna do.
那你得决定哪个更重要啊 宝贝
Well, you're gonna have to decide what's more important, baby.
你真是个淫荡的孕妇
Oh, you're a horny preggers.
是肥胖又淫荡 太恶心了
Fat and horny. It's fucking disgusting.
即使你有三百磅 我还是会爱你
If you were 300 pounds, I'd still do you.
真浪漫
So romantic.
- 我的儿子好吗?  - 没人说是个男孩啊
- How's my boy?  - Nobody said it's a boy.
我等不及看到你陪他一起玩的场面了
I can't wait to see the way you're gonna be with him.
你怎么知道的?
How do you know?
我就是知道
I just know.
我能感觉到
I can sense it.
- 希望你是对的  - 宝贝 我是对的
- I hope you're right.  - Baby, I am right.
- 喂 你爸爸联系你了吗?  - 我还没查邮箱
- Hey, did your dad get ahold of you?  - I haven't checked my e-mails.
糟糕! 好 你得挂掉然后再打给他 好不好?
Shit! Okay, you need to hang up and call him, all right?
- 为什么? 怎么了?  - 我靠 我真是自私 我竟然都没有想起来
- Why? What's wrong?  - Fuck. I'm so selfish. I wasn't even thinking.
塔雅 怎么了? 发生什么事了?
Taya, what's wrong? What happened?
你弟弟被部署了
Your little brother deployed.
你什么意思? 伞兵学校学校那边怎么了?
What do you mean? What happened to jump school?
不 他没进伞兵学校 你先挂掉然后打给你爸爸 好吗?
No, he didn't get in. You just hang up and call your dad, okay?
等等 你到底是什么意思? 部署到哪了? 他现在在哪里?
Wait. What do you mean? Deployed where? Where is he?
就在你那边
Over there.
他正在去伊拉克的路上
He's headed to Iraq.
我很抱歉 亲爱的
I'm sorry, honey.
这个拿着刀的男人 他是个约旦激进分子
The man with the blade, he's a Jordanian militant.
他由本拉登出资赞助和训练
He's funded by bin Laden. He's trained by bin Laden.
他对本拉登很忠诚
He is loyal to bin Laden.
他的名字叫扎卡维
His name is Zarqawi.
现在 这个混蛋是伊拉克境内基地组织的储君
Now, this asshole is right now the crown prince of Al-Qaeda in Iraq.
他的雇佣军"基地组织"有五千人
His mercenary army, AQI, they're 5,000 strong.
听着 这些可不是你们平时遇到的敌人
Now, these guys are not your average shit-kickers.
这些人受过良好的训练 工资也非常可观
These guys are well trained, they are well paid.
现在 他们发起了继越战后最大的城市恐怖袭击
And right now, they are waging the largest urban assault since Vietnam.
扎卡维和他的手下们 是我们的首要目标
Zarqawi and his lieutenants, these are our top priority.
现在只有一个可以把它们连根拔起的方法
Now, there is only one way to root these guys out,
就是挨家挨户的搜查
and that is to go door to door, house to house,
直到我们找到他们或者能够提供关于他们行踪消息的人
until we find them or we find someone who will give us their whereabouts.
所以 我们需要每小时清理十个建筑
So, we are going to need to clear 10 structures an hour,
我知道任务很重 也很激进
which, I know, is a lot. It's aggressive.
但空中援助可以让我们事半功倍
We're gonna be loosening things up with air support.
这是我们迄今为止的最首要的目标
This is the highest priority target we have to date.
我希望这个混蛋被击毙或者逮捕 明白吗?
I want this asshole dead or captured. Do you understand?
有问题吗?
Are there any questions?
我敢说 这些海军陆战队要是像现在这样
I'll tell you something. These marines keep rushing in like they're doing,
- 肯定会被敌人干掉的  - 他们是海军陆战队
- they're gonna have their asses shot off.  - Well, they're marines.
他们没有像我们一样接受训练 其中一半的人在六个月前都是普通老百姓
They don't get the training we do. Half these guys were civilians six months ago.
那就让我们教教他们吧 我会告诉他们团队是如何行动的
Well, let's coach them up. I'll show them how team guys do it.
- 我会带一个小队到街上  - 不 你不能那么做 我们需要你掩护射击
- I'll lead the unit on the street.  - No, can't do that. We need you on overwatch.
拜托 如果我在街上 马克 我可以...
Oh, come on. If I'm on the street, Marc, I could...
逐户搜索在这儿可是件要命的活儿 你是有救世主情结吗?
House-to-house is the deadliest job here. You got some sort of savior complex?
不 我就是想抓住那些坏家伙 但如果我看不到他们的话 我就没法射杀他们
No, I just want to get the bad guys. But if I can't see them, I can't shoot them.
听着 所有这些队员都知道你的大名 如果你在上面掩护的话 他们会觉得自己战无不胜
Look, all these guys, they know your name. And they feel invincible with you up there.
- 他们不是这样想的  - 你觉得是就是
- They're not.  - They are if they think they are.
你就继续从远处射击吧? 我们会让这些小猎犬把扎卡维嗅出来的
Why don't you keep banging on the long gun? We'll let these dogs sniff out Zarqawi.
你说基地组织有一个奥运会的狙击手
You said AQI has a sniper in the Olympics,
但是伊拉克在三次运动会中都没有一个合格的射手
but Iraq hasn't qualified a shooter in three games.
嗯 那是因为穆斯塔法不是伊拉克人
Well, that's 'cause Mustafa's not Iraqi.
他是叙利亚人
He's from Syria.
重新列队!
Regroup!
嘿 一旦你们全部进去 我就什么也看不见了
Hey, once you all gain entry, I can't see shit.
所以 慢慢来 从中间穿过你们的作战目标
So take it slow and move through your target.
- 明白了  - 爆破!
- Understood.  - Fire in the hole!
走 走 走!
Go, go, go!
该死的
Fuck this.
我要和海军陆战队员们一起扫楼
I'm gonna go clear houses with marines.
- 你来吗?  - 不 我不去
- You coming?  - Fuck no, I'm not coming.
不 哥们 我爱生活 我真的很想活着回去
No, man. I like my life. I'd actually like to make it home alive.
听着 我的工作不是去拆毁那些该死的门 对吧?
Look, it's not my job to go fucking knocking down doors, all right?
那些家伙都干错了活儿 我是不会干那傻事的
Those guys picked the wrong fucking job. I'm not doing that shit.
好吧 嗯 如果我没在底下见到你
All right, well, if I don't see you down there,
你最好保证永远都别让我看到你
you make sure I don't see you again.
嘿 介意我和你们一起前进吗?
Hey. Y'all mind if I roll with you?
嘿 哥们 我不介意和任何海豹部队成员同行
Hey, man. Any SEAL is cool by me.
你就是他们说的那个传奇人物吧 你射杀了24个人
You're that guy, the one they're calling The Legend. You got like 24 confirmed kills.
- 嗯 这是谁数的?  - 那简直太帕
- Well, who's counting?  - That's fucking bad-ass.
是的 我听说有个B队的混蛋已经赶上来了
Yeah, I heard some motherfucker in Bravo's catching up, yo.
听着 我知道你们都不是吃素的 可以肯定 但是有一些简单的技巧
Listen. I know y'all are meat-eaters, for sure, but I know a couple things,
我得教教你们 也许可以让我们大家都好好活着 你们觉得怎么样?
some simple shit I could show you. Maybe keep us above ground. What do you say?
- 行  - 好吧
- Yeah.  - All right.
说得对
Right on.
- 嘿 那是什么意思 兄弟?  - 破门手上吧
- Hey, what's that mean, bro?  - Breacher up.
- 快走  - 快趴下! 立刻趴在地板上!
- Moving.  - Get down! Get down on the ground right now!
- 都给我趴下!  - 不 不!
- Get your fucking ass down!  - No, no!
- 他不明白!  - 快趴下!
- He no understand!  - Get down!
你们为什么还在这儿? 你们应该正在撤离这片区域 你们为什么还在这儿?
Why are you here? You're supposed to be evacuating this area. Why are you still here?
- 我是西科・阿尔欧贝帝  - 西科・阿拉什么?! 你到底是谁?!
- I am Sheikh Al-Obeidi.  - Sheik Alla-who?! Who the fuck are you?!
- 这是我家! 所以我待在这儿!  - 我才不在乎这是不是你家!
- This is my home! I stay!  - I don't give a fuck it's your home!
- 这是作战区  - 先生 拜托!
- This is a war zone, sir!  - Sir, please!
- 让那小孩趴下!  - 不! 不!
- Get that kid down!  - No! No!
- 就你 先生 我来帮你  - 在后面的壁橱里找到了这些臭娘们
- You, sir. Let me help you.  - Found these bitches in the back closet.
这里欢迎你们 你们是我的客人
You are welcome here. You are my guest.
- 你这儿还有多少人?!  - 但叫那些士兵都进来
- How many more you have here?!  - But tell the soldiers to come in.
不 这个伊斯兰人就是想让我们全部进来这样就可以把我们全都炸死
No. This Hajji just wants us all in here so he can blow us up.
- 去检查他的...  - 如果他看到美国人 他就知道我们说话了
- Go check his ass for a...  - If he see American, he know we speak.
- 谁? 谁? 谁看到你和我们说话?  - 这样太危险了 请进来
- Who? Who? Who saw you talking to us?  - It's very dangerous. Please come in.
- 谁会知道我们和你说话了? 谁?!  - 他会来 他会来
- Who knows we're talking to you? Who?!  - He come. He come.
他... 他会来 他...
He... he come. He...
非常可怕 拜托
Very bad. Please.
- 这个作战目标是安全的吗?  - 是安全的
- This target's secure?  - Target secure.
让他们进来 头靠地上 手放背后
Bring them in. Get your head down on the ground. Put your hands behind your back.
现在! 现在进来!
Now! Move now!
- 拜托! 拜托!  - 你说吧 我们会和你聊聊的
- Please! Please!  - You talk, we'll talk to you.
把他带到另一个房间
Bring him in the other room.
如果他和美国士兵说了话 他们就会过来惩罚他们杀一儆百
If he talks to U.S. soldiers, they will come to his house and make examples of them.
他? 他是谁? 他是谁?
He? Who's he? Who's he?
来的那个人 他们叫他"屠夫" 他是个丧心病狂的人
The man who comes, they call "The Butcher." He's the despaired one.
是撒旦之子 是... 是魔鬼之子
Son of Shaytan, son of... son of devil.
他就像一个执法官?
Oh, he's like an enforcer?
是的 执法官
Yes, enforcer.
- 头号士兵扎卡维  - 扎卡维?
- Number-one soldier Zarqawi.  - Zarqawi?
- 扎卡维  - 是的 我们想知道扎卡维在哪
- Zarqawi.  - Yeah, we'd like to know where Zarqawi is.
你知道他在哪吗? 你告诉我们他现在在哪
You know where he is? You tell us where he is right now.
我们怎么才能抓到他?
How can we get him?
你有关于扎卡维的信息吗? 现在就告诉我们
Do you have information for us about Zarqawi? Tell us right now.
找到屠夫 就能找到扎卡维 他是他的手下
You find the Butcher, you find Zarqawi. He reports to him.
好的 我们要怎么找到他?
Okay, well, how do we find him?
好吧 我跟你说话的时候请看着我 我们要怎么找到他?
All right, look at me when I'm talking to you. Where do we find him?
我们必须了解的是这样做对他来说是有风险的 但是他会开价的
We must understand the risk to them, but he will ask for money.
- 十万美元  - 你要十万美元?
- $100,000.  - You need $100,000?
我没有证据证明有这么个家伙
I have no proof this guy exists.
法蒂玛!
Fatima!
来了
Howdy.
你好
Hello.
这就是证据
This is the proof.
好的 听着 我真的想帮你们 但是我需要一些信息
All right, look, I wanna help you out. I do. But I need something.
我需要电话号码 地址 名字 你必须给我些信息
I need phone numbers, address, names. You have to give me something.
- 长官 第一个排被制约住了  - 我们往外撤!
- Sir. First platoon's pinned down.  - Let's move out!
西科 我跟你说话的时候请看着我 嘿! 看着我! 我需要一些信息
Sheikh, look at me when I'm talking to you. Hey! Look at me! I need something.
我可以帮你 西科
I can help you out, Sheikh.
你告诉我他的名字 我们会小心的
You give me a name, and we will take care of it.
我可以向你保证 我们会保证你们的安全
I can promise you that. We will give you safety.
- 现在就告诉我们!  - 阿米尔・卡拉夫・法纳斯!
- Tell me right now!  - Amir Khalaf Fanus!
- 埃米尔・阿纳发努斯?  - 阿米尔・卡拉夫・法纳斯
- Emile Anafanoos?  - Amir Khalaf Fanus.
这是屠夫的名字
This is the given name of the Butcher.
我们相信屠夫是扎卡维手下的二把手
We believe that the Butcher is Zarqawi's number two man.
这就是你们要找的家伙
This is your guy right here.
是 但你不知道他的真名 不然你就会把它写上去了
Yeah, but you don't know his real name. Otherwise, you'd have written it up there.
我们知道很多别名
We got several aliases.
现在 如果"法纳斯"是真名...
Now, if "Fanus" is legit...
- 我们要... 我们要去见这个西科  - 他开口要十万
- We'll... we'll go see the Sheikh.  - He's asking for 100,000.
数字 但是如果他能把屠夫交出来 那就给他这么多吧
Figures. But if he delivers the Butcher, he's gonna get it.
我是国防情报局的斯尼德探员 我要查一下阿米尔・卡拉夫・法纳斯这个名字
This is agent Snead, DIA. I need a name check on an Amir Khalaf Fanus.
好的 我等着
Yeah, I'll wait.
如果我们回去的话 第三组可以做安保工作
If we're gonna go back out there, team 3 can pull security.
那是不可能的 如果我们要动钱的话 上头就会派人过来了
That's not gonna happen. Head shed's gonna want contractors on it if we're humping money.
是的 我还在 你查到了什么?
Yeah, I'm here. What do you got?
好吧 行
All right. Okay.
我们去见西科吧
Let's go see the Sheikh.
路杀
Roadkill.
你知道屠夫是扎卡维的执法官吗?
You know the Butcher is Zarqawi's enforcer?
他们说他的武器竟然是把该死的电钻
They say his weapon of choice is a fucking drill.
我在加入海军之前上过神学院
Went to seminary school before I joined the Navy.
差点就成了牧师
Was close to being a preacher.
那最后为什么没当成?
And why didn't you?
哥们 我喜欢赌博
I love to gamble, man.
喜欢那些骰子
Love those dice.
真是我喜欢的好牧师
That's my kind of preacher.
现在竟然有电话了?
It's like that now?
你没听说过吗? 我就是"传奇"
Oh, haven't you heard? I'm The Legend.
嘿 宝贝
Hey, babe.
你说对了 医生说是个男孩
You were right. The doctor says it's a boy.
什么?
What?
是个男孩!
It's a boy!
是个男孩?!
It's a boy?!
该死的 哥们 恭喜了!
Hell, yeah, man. Congratulations!
克里斯?!
Chris?!
拿上钱! 去目标地点!
Grab the money! Get to the drop!
走! 走! 把包拿着! 把包拿着!
Go! Go! Grab the bag! Grab the bag!
克里斯!
Chris!
走! 走! 快离开这儿! 我们一会儿再回来接他们
Go! Go! Get the fuck outta here! We'll come back for them.
宝贝?
Baby?
- 我听到了一声枪响  - 对
- I heard one shot.  - Check.
子弹弯了个角度 射手在300码或者更远的位置
Came in at an angle. Be 300 or more yards out.
天啊
Oh, my God.
- 你瞄准他了吗?  - 机会不大
- You got a bead on him?  - I got a tiny little window.
该死! 我看见屠夫了 他把西科的小孩弄到大街上了
Shit! I got eyes on the Butcher. He's got the Sheikh's kid on the avenue.
请求快速反应部队支援
Requesting QRF.
我们在接近高级作战目标的时候被狙击手的射击制约住了
We're being pinned down by sniper fire on approach of high value target.
坐标04536236 完毕
Grid 04536236. Over.
我想给他们放个烟雾弹保证这座楼的安全 我要去屋顶
I wanna pop a smoke 'em and secure this building. I'm going to the roof.
等等!
Hold up!
- 等等  - 再等等
- Hold.  - Holding.
走!
Go!
天啊 天啊
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
你跟他们通风报信 就和他们一起死
来吧 你这该死的混蛋!
Come on, you fucking son of a bitch!
去死!
Fuck you!
天啊 简直一团糟
Jesus Christ, what a fucking mess.
你就是个愚蠢的混蛋 你知道吗? 你究竟在想什么?
You're one dumb son of a bitch, you know that? What the hell were you thinking?
你完全没有保护好战场
You completely failed to secure the battlefield.
我要把这次任务全部暂停直到调查结束为止 回基地去吧!
I'm shutting this whole thing down pending an inquiry. Get back to base!
- 嘿 我们得组一支队伍去追他  - 不行 他们让我们停工
- Hey, we gotta set up a squad and pursue him.  - Nope, they're shutting us down.
什么意思?
What do you mean?
他们搞清楚是怎么回事之后我们才能再出来
Can't leave the wire till they figure this shit out.
他不能就那样把我们晾在这儿 嘿! 我还有三周就要回家了!
Well, he can't just leave us like that. Hey! I go home in three weeks!
哥们 那将会是漫长的三周
Man, that's gonna be a long three weeks.
- 你好吗?  - 最近怎么样 老爸?
- How are you?  - What's going on, pop?
嘿
Hey.
嘿 宝贝
Hey, baby.
我以为你死了
I thought you were dead.
对不起 我很抱歉
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- 我还以为你死了  - 嗯 我不就在这儿嘛
- I thought you were dead.  - Well, I'm right here.
看着我
Look at me.
- 你没事吧?  - 没事
- You all right?  - Yeah.
你是我见过的最美的风景
You're the most beautiful thing I've ever seen.
我的身体里长着个外星人
I have an alien growing inside me.
- 有个陌生的男人在我的卧室里  - 嗯 是我们的卧室
- And there's a strange man in my bedroom.  - Well, it's our bedroom.
你的手感觉不一样了
Your hands feel different.
没有 我的手... 我的手就是这样的啊
Oh, no. They're... they're my hands.
- 该死的我为什么这么紧张?  - 嗯 我也是
- Why am I so fucking nervous?  - Well, I am, too.
- 不 你才没有 你在说谎  - 不 真的紧张 我发誓
- No, you're not. You're lying.  - Yes, I am. I swear.
我怎么知道那里的外星人不会出来抓住我?
How do I know some alien in there is not gonna come out and grab me?
在半夜的时候
In the middle of the night.
那我就不得不...
Then I'm gonna have to...
哽咽着让他出来
choke him out.
会没事的
It's gonna be okay.
- 你保证?  - 是的 当然
- Promise?  - Yeah, of course.
你为什么对我这么好?
Why're you so good with me?
嘿 宝贝 出去走走会比较好
Hey, babe. It might be nice to get out.
你在听我说话吗?
You listening to me?
克里斯
Chris.
亲爱的 你今天打算干什么?
What do you wanna do today, hon?
我想我们就在家里休息吧
I thought we could just relax here.
好的 就按你说的做
Okay, we do that.
让我们休息一下
Let's relax.
- 你在干什么?  - 把脚放你身上啊
- What're you doing?  - Putting my foot on you.
嗯 你知道 那是... 那地方通到我的心脏
Well, you know that's... that's the way to my heart.
我过来咯
I'm coming over.
看起来很棒
And that looks great.
看 他在摸自己的鼻子
Look. He's touching his nose.
- 你感觉如何?  - 感觉还行 想让他出来 我觉得很疲惫
- How are you feeling?  - I'm all right. I just want him out. I'm tired.
- 嗯 可能是从现在开始的任何一天  - 希望如此
- Well, it's gonna be any day now.  - I hope so.
你呢 凯尔先生? 感觉如何?
How 'bout you, Mr. Kyle? How're you feeling?
我感觉挺好的 谢谢你 夫人
I'm feeling good. Thank you, ma'am.
我想减压会挺难的
I imagine it's hard to decompress.
真的不会 不会
Not really. No.
这是我们头一回出家门
This is the first time we've left the house.
回家我很开心 嗯
I'm happy to be home. Yeah.
来 把这个系上 好吗?
Here, put this on for me, would ya?
我想如果你想做些检查的话 检查我的膝盖会比较合适
I think if you wanna check anything out, you may wanna check out these knees.
- 你抽烟吗?  - 不抽 夫人
- Are you a smoker?  - No, ma'am.
- 你喝酒吗?  - 只在口渴的时候喝
- You drink?  - Only when I'm thirsty.
高压170低压110
That's 170/110.
- 天啊 克里斯  - 这算很高吗?
- Jesus Christ, Chris.  - Is that high?
如果你刚喝完14杯咖啡的话那就不算高 但是你现在正好好地坐着...
Not if you've just had 14 cups of coffee. But for someone who is sitting down...
谢谢你... 帮我检查 我会再去检查的
Oh, I appreciate you... taking a look at that. I'll look into it.
- 谢谢  - 你会去检查吗?
- Thank you.  - Will you look into it?
是的
Yeah.
你刚刚在那儿是在给我捣乱
You sabotaged me back there.
那我应该怎么做? 你一直不说话 表现出一幅一切都很好的样子
What am I supposed to do? You're not talking. You act like it's all okay.
- 没事的 我很好  - 克里斯 你出了问题 好吗?
- It is okay. I'm fine.  - You're not fine, Chris, all right?
你的血压都高压170低压110了 这简直...
Your blood pressure is, like, fucking 170/110. It's like...
我正在高速路上开车 现在阳光灿烂 温度72度
I'm driving down the freeway. It's sunny. It's 72 degrees.
我很好 有一场战争正在进行 有人正在死去
I'm fine. There's a war going on. There's people dying.
没有人谈起它 就像它甚至没在进行一样
No one's even talking about that. It's like it's not even happening.
我们都在打电话 过着我们简单又单纯的生活
We're all on our cell phones, living our simple, simplistic lives.
- 新闻甚至都没有报道 没有人在意  - 克里斯
- It's not even on the news. No one cares.  - Chris.
战争正在进行着但我却在去商场的路上
There's a war going on and I'm headed to the mall.
- 克里斯 我要生了  - 我不应该在这儿
- Chris. It's happening.  - I'm not supposed to be here.
- 怎么了? 你还好吗?  - 我要生了
- What's wrong? You okay?  - It's happening.
该死 好的 我们往回走
Shit. Okay. I'm gonna go back.
- 你真是疯了! 你知道吗?  - 没事的 嘿 宝贝 宝贝
- You're fucking crazy! You know that?  - It's okay. Hey! Baby, baby.
- 天啊 宝贝  - 你看起来真美
- Oh, my God. Baby.  - You look beautiful.
竟然要生了
It's fucking happening.
我的孩子
Oh, my baby.
快看你的妈妈
Look at your mama.
- 嘿  - 嗨 宝贝
- Hey.  - Hi, baby.
- 嘿 小家伙  - 嘿 宝贝
- Hey, little guy.  - Hey, baby.
嘿 小家伙 我们真是好样的
Hey, little guy. Look what we did.
我们真是好样的 瞧瞧我们的结晶
Look what we did. Look what we made.
瞧瞧我们的结晶
Look what we made.
宝贝在哭 我以为你会去哄他
The baby's crying. I thought you were gonna get him.
不 不用关掉 我已经看到了
No, don't bother turning it off. I already watched it.
我得确保你没有伊拉克女朋友给你发来性感视频
Had to make sure you didn't have an Iraqi girlfriend sending you sexy videos.
那是个录下自己射杀过程的狙击手 他叫穆斯塔法
That's a sniper recording his kills. That's Mustafa.
他把那鬼东西拿出来卖 那些都是美国士兵
He sells that shit on the street. Those are American soldiers.
我们打电话的那天 是他吗? 是吗?
That day that we were on the phone, was that him? Was it?
克里斯 说说吧 你这种什么都不说的方式是没法保护到我的
Chris, just talk about it. You're not protecting me by not talking about it.
不 我不希望你的头脑里出现那些画面 你知道吗?
No, I don't want you getting that in your head, ya understand?
我想象中的画面比你可能告诉我的还要糟
Well, my imagination is so much worse than anything you could tell me.
- 克里斯  - 宝贝 他们就是群该死的野蛮人
- Chris.  - Babe, They're fucking savages.
和他们没关系
It's not about them.
这关系到我们自己
It's about us.
什么?
What?
你必须要回到我们身边
You have to make it back to us.
懂吗?
Okay?
第二次海外部署
欢迎回来 士官长 琼斯上校正等着你呢 旅途怎么样?
Welcome home, chief. Colonel Jones is waiting. How was the flight?
- 比圣诞节都长  - 我就知道
- Damn longer than Christmas.  - I bet.
- 你能等一下吗?  - 行 快点
- Hey. Can you wait a second?  - All right. Hurry up.
嘿 大兵!
Hey, grunt!
- 克里斯?  - 嗨 兄弟!
- Chris?  - Hey, brother!
嗨
Hi.
你身体怎么样? 没受什么伤吧?
You all right? You in one piece?
我听说你在这边无人可敌 所有人都这么说
I heard you been kicking ass out here, man. All the guys, that's what they've been saying.
- 是吗 他们是这么说的?  - 嗯
- Yeah, that's what they say?  - Yeah.
你还好吗? 见到你我真高兴
How ya doing? You okay? Oh, shit, it's good to see you.
你是我的英雄 哥哥 一直都是
You're my hero, bro. Okay? You always have been.
走吧 凯尔! 上校等着呢!
Let's go, Kyle! Colonel's waiting!
传奇? 是吗?
The Legend? Huh?
- 怎么了? 你还好吗?  - 我要错过飞机了
- What happened? You all right?  - Man, I'm gonna miss my ride.
出什么事了?
Hey, what happened?
我就是有点累 哥 我... 我想回家
I'm just tired, man. I'm... I'm going home.
你是我的骄傲
I'm proud of you.
也是爸爸的骄傲
Dad is, too. Dad's proud of you.
这该死的地方
Fuck this place.
- 你说什么?  - 这该死的地方
- What'd you say?  - Fuck this place.
士官长 我们得走了! 走吧!
Chief, we got to move! Let's go!
- 你现在是士官长了 恭喜  - 谢谢您 长官
- You made chief. Congratulations.  - Thank you, sir.
格朗斯基已经走了 许多关键人物也是 我们现在正在面对一个全新的环境
Gronski's gone. A lot of the top brass are. Running off a new playbook now.
我研究了上个世纪的叛乱
I've studied insurgencies for the last decade.
我知道自第一个世纪以来他们扔的每一块石头
I know every stone thrown since before the first century.
敌人的心理决定了战争的成与败
These wars are won and lost in the minds of our enemy.
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
这是你吗?
That you?
那是个十字军徽章 是的 长官
That's a crusader cross. Yes, sir.
嗯
Yeah.
你现在是伊拉克的头号通缉犯了
You're now the most wanted man in Iraq.
你的头值18万 恭喜啊
There's 180,000 on your head. Congrats.
先别告诉我妻子 她可能会立刻干掉我
Well, don't tell my wife. She might take that number right now.
我理解你想组织一支直接行动小队去追杀那个屠夫的想法
I understand you wanna put together a direct action squad to hunt the Butcher.
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
我们收集的一些情报透露了他的行动地点
We got some Intel indicating his area of operations.
我想让你去恐吓一下那些野蛮人...
I want you to put the fear of God into these savages...
并且找到这个混蛋
and find his ass.
好的 长官
Yes, sir.
好了 咱们去把这个混蛋找出来吧
All right, let's go get this motherfucker.
这会是我们离开前的一个突击测验
Gonna be a pop quiz before we leave.
- 下次别吹牛了 大传奇  - 你说什么?
- Small words next time, big legend. - What'd you say?
下次别吹牛了
Small words next time.
你要是想听那些故事的话我可以给你讲
I'll tell you those stories if you want 'em.
- 一大堆幻灯片都说不完 哥们 -  谢谢 比格斯
- One hell of a PowerPoint, man. - Oh, thanks, Biggles.
你总得说些什么 混蛋
Always gotta say something, motherfucker.
- 你的那本圣经防弹吗?  - 就是我放在胸口的那一本?
- That Bible of yours, is that bulletproof?  - What, the one I put in here?
嗯 我只是... 我从来没见你打开过 我以为它能防弹...
Yeah. I just... I never saw you open it. I assumed...
上帝 国家 家庭 是吗?
God, country, family, right?
你有神吗?
You got a God?
我有神? 你越来越过分了啊?
I got a God? You getting weird on me?
你知道吗 在俄勒冈州长大 我们在自家财产周围立了电篱笆
You know, growing up in Oregon, we had this electric fence around our property.
孩子们会抓住它然后看谁坚持的时间最长
Us kids'd grab onto it and see who could hold on the longest.
战争的感觉和它有点像
War feels kinda like that.
把闪电击入你的骨头 让你很难去抓住别的东西
Puts lightning in your bones and makes it hard to hold on to anything else.
嘿 兄弟 你想袖手旁观吗?
Hey, man, you need to sit this one out?
我只是想相信我们正在做的事情
I just wanna believe in what we're doing here.
这里的邪恶 我们看到它了
Oh, there's evil here. We've seen it.
是啊 到处是有邪恶势力
Yeah. There's evil everywhere.
你想让这些混蛋们去圣迭戈或是纽约吗?
Oh, you want these motherfuckers to come to San Diego or New York?
我们保护的不止是这片土地
We're protecting more than just this dirt.
好吧
All right.
我们去把这个混蛋杀了吧
Let's go kill this fucker.
找到了 那边那个建筑物就是
Bingo. It's the building right here.
东面的每一栋公寓都正对着那个餐厅
Any apartment on the east side faces the restaurant.
进去 长官 走 走 走
Go in, sir. Go, go, go.
安全
Clear.
另一个门
Other door.
- 好 好 好  - 趴在地上
- Okay, okay. Okay.  - Get down on the ground right now.
- 把手放在背后  - 好
- Put your hands behind your back.  - Okay.
目标安全
Target secure.
窗户就交给我吧 克里斯
I got the window, Chris.
- 武装警戒 弟兄们  - 好 咱们走吧
- Set security, boys.  - All right, let's get set up.
注意角落
Corner.
咱们把他们放进别的房间吧
Let's move them into the other room.
你们问问他认识这个人吗 你记得这个人吗?
Y'all ask if he knows him. You recognize this guy?
他说他不记得
He says he does not.
你呢 小伙子 你认识他吗?
How 'bout you, son? You recognize this face?
你确定吗?
You sure?
好吧 你告诉他们 除非我们离开 不然他们哪儿都不能去
Well, you know, you make sure you tell 'em they're not gonna go anywhere until we do.
你在留意一下那个窗户
Hey, you keep eyes on that window.
确保给每个经过的人照相
Make sure you take pictures of anybody coming and going.
有什么收获没有?
What do we got?
- 一共来了16个到了服役年龄的男性  - 16个?
- 16 military-aged males have gone in.  - 16?
是的 他们比麦当劳接待的客人都多
Yeah, they serve more customers than a fucking McDonald's.
过来看看这个
Here, check this out.
他还在那里面吗?
Is he still in there?
他进来了一次 他还在那 但我们想要进去不容易
I clocked one point of entry. He's in there, but it's not gonna be an easy breach.
那我可不知道 哥们
Oh, I don't know about that, man.
大概看到了传奇就直接放他进来了 他可是大红大紫的名流
Probably see The Legend and just let him right in, you know, big-time celebrity.
布尔卡: 一些国家中穆斯林女子在公共场所穿戴的面纱女袍
让他在她们的布尔卡上面签名 在她们孩子的生日派对上现身
Ask him to sign their burka. Appear at their child's birthday parties.
嘿 你怎么回事? 我都... 我都没有自吹自擂
Hey, what is your problem? I didn't... I didn't promote myself.
你当然没有 混蛋 我在帮你出名呢
Yeah, no shit, motherfucker. I did that for you.
要是我没有给你起什么神话一类的绰号 你连士官长都当不上
You woulda never made chief if I hadn't nicknamed you the fucking myth or some shit.
他邀请你去参加他的古尔邦晚宴(伊斯兰重要节日)
He invites you to join him for an Eid Al Adha supper.
他说"在这一天 每个人都会在我的桌子上有一个位置"
He says, "on this day, everyone has a seat at my table."
他真是慷慨大方
Oh, that's pretty generous of him.
那真是 就差一点
That was, like, close, man.
拿一根黄瓜 然后把它放进一个有醋的盆里
Take a cucumber. Take cucumber and put it in a tub with vinegar.
对
Yeah.
再把它插进红辣椒和柠檬里 然后泡一晚上
Stick in cayenne pepper and a lemon... and let it soak overnight.
就是那样 还要再加一点伏特加 就这么做 你想试试吗?
It's that, and just add vodka. That's the idea. You wanna get in on it?
做吧 哥们 我第一个参加
Let's do it, dude. I'm a ground-floor investor.
比格斯 你这辈子可是从来没有做过饭啊
Biggles, you never cooked a day in your life.
伙计 这才是问题所在
Dude, that was the real question.
- 问题就出在这了  - 那些人都落在我们后面了
- That was super real.  - All these random people getting behind us.
天啊 我落在神话后面了
Oh, my God, I fell in behind the myth.
天啊
Holy shit.
- 别这样 哥们 有点脑子  - 我得去洗洗手
- Come on, man. Get some brains.  - I gotta wash my hands.
嘿 干什么呢!
Hey, hey, hey!
- 快去看看  - 别动地方 别动
- Go check that out.  - Stay right here. Stay here.
- 怎么回事?  - 比格斯 帮帮我
- Hey, what the fuck?!  - Biggles, help me out.
看见没 伊军
See that, Muj?
你看到了吗?
You see that?
- 到底发生什么了?  - 把翻译带过来
- What the fuck's going on?  - Bring the terp in.
天啊
Oh, shit.
现在你和他说 他要么被送去监狱
All right. Now you tell him that he's gonna be sent off to detention
并接受伊拉克法庭对他的指控
and the Iraqi courts can decide what to do with him.
要么帮我们打进楼下的饭店
Or he can help us get inside of that restaurant downstairs.
告诉他 让他自己选
You tell him. Say it's his choice.
就是那
That's it.
安全
All clear.
好 行动
Good, good. Moving.
攻击小队就绪
Assault team set.
- 我们紧跟上了 安全部署就位  - 目标正在移动
- We're in tight. Security set.  - Package is moving.
距离十五米
15 meters out.
十米
10 meters.
五米
5 meters.
他在敲门
He's knocking.
等等
Hold.
他们在检查他
They're vetting him.
再见了 伊军
Lights out, Muj.
行动 行动
Execute. Execute.
手雷! 手雷!
Frag out! Frag out!
- 比格斯 有人从后面来吗?  - 没有
- Biggles, anything coming out the back?  - Negative. No
该死
Oh, shit.
- D 把他放下来  - 好的
- "D," take him down.  - Got him.
把他放下来
Get him down.
该死!
Oh, shit!
我们发现了一个隧道 注意身后 眼睛睁大了
We found a tunnel. Watch your back. Keep your eyes open.
有敌人! 有敌人!
Contact! Contact!
有敌人! 后退!
Contact! Drop back!
东面! 东面有火箭筒！
White-side! RPG on the white-side!
屠夫正在移动
Butcher's on the move.
重复 屠夫在移动 我在追赶
Repeat, Butcher's on the move. I'm in pursuit.
屠夫死了 全体集合
Butcher's down. Move in your position.
我是说我本想让他去蹲监狱 这是他自己的选择
I mean, I offered him detention. It was his choice.
他选错边了 这很简单 战争之雾
Picked the wrong side. It's all there is to it. Fog of war.
哟 克里斯! 别管它了 我们走吧 情况越来越糟了
Yo, Chris! Fuck it, man. Let's go. Shit's getting hairy.
长官 有武装反叛分子正在往这边走 我们得走了
Sir, we have armed insurgents moving this way. We need to make tracks.
麻烦事大了 长官
Heck of a job there, chief.
- 你还想再来一个吗 还是你不要了?  - 看 这是什么?
- You want another one, or are you good?  - Look. What is this?
不 它给你什么你就得拿什么 它就是这样的原理
No. Well, you get what it gives you. That's how this thing works.
如果你想要那个的话 你是不会拿到它的
You don't get that one, if that's the one you want.
我喜欢那个
I like that.
那个好 它很强壮
That's good. That's strong.
- 克里斯・凯尔 过来 你的卡车修好了  - 你可以随便拧它了
- Chris Kyle, come on. Your truck's ready.  - You can move that all you want.
你的卡车修好了 不... 不可能
Your truck's ready. Im... impossible.
- 请把信用卡给我  - 真好玩
- Give me your credit card.  - Okay. Interesting.
- 我想我已经给你了  - 哦 是的
- I already gave it to ya, I think.  - Oh, right.
干什么呢? 快把它从地上捡起来
What? Hey, just pick that up off the floor.
一个都不要落下 嗯 你那边落了一个
Make sure you get all of them up. Well, you got one back here.
打扰了 先生?
Excuse me, sir?
- 您是克里斯・凯尔士官长吗?  - 是的 先生
- Are you chief Chris Kyle?  - Yes, sir.
我叫麦兹 我们在费卢杰见过 您救了我的命
My name is Mads. We met in Fallujah. You saved my life.
- 我吗?  - 是的 长官
- I did?  - Yes, sir.
我们被困在了一栋房子里 直到您带了海军陆战一队过来
We were stuck in a house until you came in with the 1st marines.
是您把我背了出来
You were the one that carried me out.
海军陆战队救了我们的小命不止一次呢
Oh, wow. Well, the marines saved our ass plenty of times.
- 你怎么样? 还好吗? 能坚持住吗?  - 我很好
- How are you? You all right? You holding up?  - Great. Yeah.
我... 我只是很感激我能活下来 之前并不是...
I'm... I'm just grateful to be alive. It hasn't been...
之前并不是很容易
It hasn't been easy.
你知道的
Well, you know.
好多人并不只是失去了一条腿那么简单
A lot of guys lost more than just a leg.
你失去朋友了吗?
Did you lose some friends?
嗯 那个我也失去了 但是我指的是活下来的人
Well, that, too. But I'm talking 'bout the guys that lived.
那些活下来的人 但是他们却... 却没有回来 你知道吗?
That made it back, but they're just not... they're just not back, you know?
- 他们看起来很糟糕  - 是的
- They can't seem to get right.  - Yeah.
你为什么不去一下弗吉尼亚州? 他们会喜欢你的
Why don't you come down to the V.A. sometime? The guys would love it.
他们都知道"传奇"是谁
They all know who The Legend is.
- 是啊 听起来不错  - 嗨 哥们
- Yeah, that sounds like a good idea.  - Hey, buddy.
能跟你说句话吗?
Can I tell you something?
你爸爸 他是一个英雄
Your dad? He's a hero.
是的 他救了我的命 他还...
That's right. He saved my life, and he...
帮我回到了我的小女儿身边
he helped me get back to my little girl.
- 所以 谢谢你把他借给我  - 好的
- So, thank you for lending him to us.  - Okay.
没有他我都不会在这里
I wouldn't be here without him.
我的家庭感谢您的付出
My family thanks you for your service.
好的 谢谢 照顾好自己
Okay, thank you. All right. Take care of yourself.
- 很高兴再次见到您  - 好了
- It's great to see you again.  - All right.
- 有时间的话来趟弗吉尼亚州  - 好的
- Come down to the V.A. sometime.  - Okay. Yeah.
把你的小蜥蜴拿上吧
Grab your little lizard up there.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 不客气  - 祝你一天好心情
- You're welcome.  - Have a good day.
- 你也是  - 好的
- You have a good day.  - Okay.
咱们去看你妹妹吧 小乖乖
All right, let's go meet your sister, bubba.
嘿 有人帮帮忙吗? 我的女儿在哭啊
Hey. Some help here? My daughter's crying.
那是我的女儿 我觉得她在哭
That's my daughter over there. I think she's crying.
麻烦帮我照看一下好吗? 不好意思
Can you help tend to her, please? Excuse me.
嘿 你要去哪?
Hey! Hey, where you going?
嘿!
Hey!
求你去照看下我女儿 行吗?
Hey, will you tend to my daughter, please?
说你呢!
Hey!
快去照看我女儿! 快!
Hey! Tend to my daughter, please! Right now!
我在自己创造回忆
I'm making memories by myself.
没有人可以和我分享它
I have no one to share them with.
是啊 我们活了一辈子就为了它
Yeah, well, we got our whole lives for that.
是从什么时候开始的?
When does that start?
就算你人在这的时候 你的心也不在这
Even when you're here, you're not here.
我能看到你 感觉到你
I see you. I feel you.
但是你心就不在这里
But you're not here.
所以我很讨厌你的团队
I hate the teams for it.
真的
I do.
你是我的丈夫
You're my husband.
你是孩子们的爸爸 但他们却会把你送回战场
You're the father of my children, but they're the ones that pull you back.
嗯 听着... 他们不能等 我们能
Yeah, but, you see, they... they can't wait, and we can.
如果你认为这场战争并没有改变你 那么你就大错特错了
If you think this war isn't changing you, you're wrong.
你只活在战火中
You can only circle the flame so long.
这是事实
It's true.
呼叫凯迪拉克
Cadillac 31 actual,
第三次海外部署
我们正在马里兰街上追踪屠夫 完毕
we're tailing the Butcher's courier currently on Maryland street. Over.
嘿! 我买到戒指了
Hey! Got the ring.
从哪? 这里吗?
From where? From here?
是啊 当然 这边便宜好多
Yeah, man. Fuck, yeah. It's so much cheaper here.
血钻: 战区开采的钻石 其利润被用于支持恐怖分子
哥们 你居然从野蛮人手中买戒指? 你怎么知道它是不是血钻?
Dude, you bought it from savages? How do you know it's not a blood diamond?
是不是血钻关你什么事?
Oh, what the fuck do you care, man?
你在这片土地上洒这么多热血 你是传奇
You've spilled so much blood over here. You're The Legend.
我的热血可不是为了一块石头而流的
Oh, that's not for a rock.
随便你吧
What the fuck ever, man.
你太虚伪了
That's just hypocritical.
慢点 别 别靠太近
Hey, ease up on that. No, don't get too close.
- 好吧 我知道了  - 你告诉她你是从哪里买的钻戒了吗?
- All right. Hey, I know.  - Did you tell her where you bought it from?
Zales: 美国著名钻石零售商
当然没有 我就说我是在Zales上面买的
Fuck no. I'm gonna tell her I got that shit from Zales.
你还跟着我们吗 曲奇?
Hey, you still with us, Cookie?
还有半个街区 我们都迫不及待了
Just a half block back, baby. We are wet and ready, big giggles.
听好了 D...
You know, "D"...
我预言 二十年之后我们会再相聚...
I predict in 20 years, we're gonna have a reunion...
你会跟一爷们结婚
and you'll be married to a dude.
前提是你会做饭打扫卫生
As long as you cook and clean.
- 你看他们  - 我靠
- Now, there they are.  - Oh, shit.
穆斯塔法把眼线放出来了
Mustafa's got his peepers out.
哥们 这是凯瑟・素兹
This motherfucker is Keyser fucking Soze, bro.
下次逮到机会 千万别打偏了 好吗?
Hey, next time you get a clear shot, you try not to miss him, all right?
要不是忙着救你 我早就在那窄街弄死他了
Well, I would've gotten him in the alleyway if I didn't have to save your ass.
那你会当我的伴郎吗?
So you gonna be my best man?
就我一个? 还是有别人一起?
Oh, just me? Or is it gonna be everybody else, too?
伴郎只有一个
There's only gonna be one best man, dude.
一号车遭到攻击
Vehicle 1 taking fire.
- 开火  - 来了
- Come on, give me a shot.  - All right.
比格斯 前进
Biggles, move.
安全
Clear.
跟我来一个
One on me.
我们抓住他了
We got him.
车内安全
Vehicle is secure.
设置警戒 克里斯
Set security, Chris.
没事
Nope.
房顶安全
Rooftop secure.
你就不怕她带着去Zales
Aren't you worried that she's gonna take that thing to Zales,
看看你花了多少钱?
find out how much you spent?
- 之前我一点也不担心  - 设置警戒
- Well, no, I wasn't.  - Set security.
- 你这么一说我有点怕  - 你应该怕
- Now I'm a little worried about it.  - You should be.
什么意思 她能靠那钻石找到Zales去?
What do you mean, she can trace the diamond to Zales?
我可不觉得...
I don't think that's gonna...
没事吧? 兄弟 你没事
You okay, buddy? You're all right.
有人受伤 比格斯受伤了 西北角屋顶!
Got a man down. Biggles is down. Northwest corner, rooftop!
坚持住 兄弟
Hang in there, bud.
我需要一个医护兵!
I need a corpsman right now!
没事的 兄弟 我们把你带到楼下去
Okay, bubba. We're gonna pick you up and take you downstairs.
我能走
I can walk.
把他带上车 把他带上车
Get him in the Humvee. Get him in the Humvee.
你先扶他一下
Breaking off.
我来扶 我来扶
I got him. I got him.
- 进去 坚持住 比格斯  - 该死
- Come on. Get in. Hang in there, Biggles.  - Fuck.
坚持住 比格斯
Hang in there, Biggles.
Hang in, Biggles.
- 没事的  - 对不起 兄弟
- It's okay.  - Shit, I'm sorry, man.
什么对不起? 我们去屋顶都怪我
For what? What are you sorry for? It's my fault we went on that roof.
我会死吗?
Am I gonna die?
当然不会 比格斯 你是蛙人 蛙人从来不会死
Fuck no, Biggles. You're a fucking frogman. Frogmen don't fucking die.
在伤口里放点沙子 再给你一水壶的水
Gonna put some sand in this fucking cut. We'll get you a fucking canteen of water.
你就会没事了 比格斯 坚持住
You're gonna be fucking fine, Biggles. Hang in there.
克里斯 你保证她能拿到戒指 好吗?
Hey, Chris. You make sure she gets that ring, all right?
当然
Sure will.
减弱吸力 把牵开器递给我
All right, let's decrease suction. The retractor, please.
增加输血量 拍片什么时候能好?
More blood. How long before we get film on him?
还需要血 三号血给我
We need another unit of blood. Give me a 3 only.
- 注射生理盐水...  - 增加吸力
- All right, saline... now.  - More suction.
- 你摁着这里  - 好
- Hold your hands right here.  - Okay.
血型和血流测量 我需要这些数据
Type and cross. I need those numbers now.
你看到子弹是从哪来的了吗?
Did you see where it came from?
一千多米开外
Yeah, it was more than 1,000 meters out.
敌方只有一个狙击手能打中这一枪
Only one enemy sniper coulda made that shot.
他能撑下来吗?
Will he make it?
鬼门关走了一遭 血压一度降到了48
Took a round off the feed tray cover. Was 48.
不太乐观
Doesn't look good.
这是第一个受伤的海豹突击队员 长官
That's the first SEAL hit, sir.
操!
Fuck!
有个司机是我们的线人 他说七座建筑之外有一个大本营
Shi'a cab driver we source is saying there's a stronghold seven doors down.
海军陆战队依然能掩护你们
Marine units covered your exfil are still engaged there.
是继续还是退出你们自己定 我能理解
I can understand if you want to stand down and regroup. It's up to you.
以牙还牙
Lex talionis.
以眼还眼
Eye for an eye.
我们杀回去
We're going back out.
- 必须的  - 肯定
- Fucking "A."  - Fuck, yes.
出发
Let's go.
开始了
It's on.
嘿!
Hey!
还有两公里
Two klicks out.
走廊安全
Hallway clear.
左侧有爆炸痕迹
On the left. Bumping.
走廊
Hallway.
走廊安全 左侧
Hallway clear. On the left.
安全
Clear.
一切正常
All clear.
安全
马克 看来离开的人很着急
Hey, Marc. Looks like someone left in a hurry.
- 有人受伤!  - 守好窗户!
- Man down!  - Cover the window!
有人受伤!
Man down!
- 看好窗户!  - 看好窗户!
- Cut that window!  - Cut that window!
坚持住 马克
Come on, Marc.
我们走 我在这 看着我 快看着我
Let's go, buddy. I got you, man. I got you. Look at me. Look at me.
有我在
I got you.
哥们 马克死了
Marc's gone, bro.
一名海豹突击队员伤亡 尽快派辆车
I got one SEAL down. I need cabs back immediately.
我们要把他带回去
We gotta fucking move him.
"有些人追求荣耀
"Glory is something some men chase,
而另一些人却因此误入歧途
and others find themselves stumbling upon
自己却毫无察觉
not expecting to find it.
无论如何 一个人找到自己存在的价值
Either way, it is a noble gesture that one...
都是一件高尚的事
finds bestowed upon them.
我想问的是 荣耀是何时腐朽发霉而变成一场十字军东征的?
My question is, when does glory fade away and become a wrongful crusade?
又或者是能将人消耗殆尽的
Or an unjustified means by which consumes one...
自私手段?
completely? I've...
我亲历战争...
seen war...
我也曾见证... 死亡"
and I've seen... death."
全体都有 立正!
Detail. Ten-hut!
举枪!
Port arms!
预备!
Ready!
瞄准
Aim.
开火!
Fire!
预备
Ready.
瞄准
Aim.
开火!
Fire!
预备
Ready.
瞄准 开火!
Aim. Fire!
举枪致敬!
Present arms!
那封信是马克两周前写的
Marc wrote that letter two weeks ago.
他跟你说过什么吗?
Did he say any of that to you?
克里斯 我想知道你怎么看那封信
Chris, I wanna know what you thought of his letter.
基地组织的线人发来了线报 然后... 比格斯就中了弹
An AQI informant had called in a tip, and... Biggles had just been shot.
我们当时在执行任务 然后就遇到了埋伏
We were operating out of emotion, and we just walked right into an ambush.
可他的死和这些没有关系
But that's not what killed him.
是那封信 是那封信杀了马克
That letter did. That letter killed Marc.
他... 他放松了 也为此付出了代价
He just... he let go, and he paid the price for it.
在这签字吗?
Sign in here?
哥们
Hey, buddy.
- 是克里斯吗?  - 是我
- Hey, Chris?  - Yeah.
- 你在哪 哥们?  - 我就在这 就在这
- Where you at, man?  - I'm right here. I'm right here.
- 你瞎得跟个蝙蝠似的  - 是啊 胀死了
- Shit, you're blind as a bat. - Yeah, it fucking blows.
- 不过他们说我这脸能修好  - 谢天谢地
- They say they're gonna fix my face, though.  - Oh, thank God.
- 是时候了 你这脸真该修修了  - 太早了 哥们
- About time. Your face needs some fixing.  - It's too soon, man.
- 这还早?  - 太早了
- It is too soon?  - Way too soon.
- 我听说你求婚了  - 是啊
- Hey, I heard you proposed.  - Yeah.
太好了 那个钻石你没说是...
Well, good for you. You didn't tell her you bought that diamond...
- 你说是在Zales买的吧?  - 不是
- you told her you bought it at Zales, right?  - No.
- 没说?  - 不是不是 买了个新的
- You didn't?  - No. No, got a new one.
这个比较小 她爸帮了我一把
It's a smaller one. Her dad helped me out with it.
- 好事啊  - 是啊
- Oh, nice.  - Yeah.
真好
Oh, good.
她不愿意离开我
She wouldn't leave me, bro.
我让她走 可她就是不离开我
I told her to go, and she wouldn't leave.
对她太不公平了
She's getting a raw fucking deal.
干嘛这么说? 别这样 她还有你
Why would you say that? Don't say that. She's got you.
- 你那五厘米都是她的  - 五厘米
- All two inches of you.  - Two inches.
跟你说 我很庆幸出事的是我不是你
Yeah, you know, I'm glad this happened to me and not you.
- 你肯定受不了  - 也许你说得对
- Ain't no way you coulda handled it.  - Yeah, you're probably right.
他们说你是美国军队历史上最致命的狙击手
So they say you're the deadliest sniper in U.S. military history.
- 是吗  - 我听说是
- Oh, is that right?  - That's what I heard.
- 那群货回到了萨德尔市  - 别去了
- The bad guys ended up in Sadr City.  - You're not going back.
要去 我们要把他们赶尽杀绝
Yeah, we are. We're gonna wall 'em in and hunt 'em down.
算了吧 哥们 没必要这样的
Nah, come on, man. You don't have to do that.
必须这样 你是我的兄弟
Oh, we have to do that. You're my brother.
他们要为对你的所作所为付出代价
And they're gonna fucking pay for what they did to you.
好啊 传奇
Hooyah, Legend.
太好了
Fucking hooyah.
如果我出事了 别管我
Something happens to me, you'd be all right.
去找别人
You'd find someone else.
你想死吗?
Do you wanna die?
就这样是吗?
Is that what it is?
不想
No.
那告诉我
Then just tell me.
告诉我为什么要这样
Tell me why you do it.
- 不是  - 我想知道
- Oh, come on.  - I wanna understand.
亲爱的 我是为了你 这都是为了保护你
Babe, I do it for you. You know that. I do it to protect you.
- 你并没有  - 我确实是
- No, you don't.  - Yes, I do.
我就在这
I'm here.
你的家人都在这 你的孩子就像没有父亲
Your family is here. Your children have no father.
- 我知道 可是我要效忠国家  - 真能扯淡!
- Well, I have to serve my country.  - That is such fucking bullshit!
- 不是扯淡  - 你不知道什么时候该脱身
- No, it's not.  - You don't know when to quit.
你做了分内的事 我们的牺牲足够多了 你得让别人去
You did your part. We've sacrificed enough. You let somebody else go.
- 让别人去?  - 对
- Let somebody else go?  - Yeah.
- 我接受不了  - 那就找个法子接受
- I couldn't live with myself.  - Yeah, well, you find a way.
必须找
You have to.
我要你重新变回正常人
Okay, I need you to be human again.
我需要你
I need you here.
亲爱的 我需要你
Baby, I need you here.
如果你离开...
If you leave again...
你回来的时候 也许我们就不在了
I don't think we'll be here when you get back.
来吧
Come here.
第四次海外部署
克里斯 天啊
Chris. Oh, man.
我们已经连着三晚被打退回来了
We've been shot off position three nights in a row, man.
费卢杰很惨 拉马迪 更惨
Fallujah was bad. Ramadi was worse.
- 简直就是圣经 克里斯  - 这还有别的惩罚者吗?
- This shit is fucking biblical, Chris.  - Is there any other punishers here?
松鼠走了 道博倒是想回来 但他老婆不同意
Squirrel cycled out. And Dauber was coming back, but his wife knocked him up.
我要是带个假发回去 我老婆肯定弄死我 克里斯
And if I bring home another rug, my wife'll murder my motherfucking ass, Chris.
- 为了团队 是吧?  - 为了团队
- Teams and shit, right?  - Teams and shit.
比格斯的事真是个打击
Man, that Biggles news hit hard, man.
走之前我还去医院看他了 他啥也看不见
I went to see him in the hospital before I left. Motherfucker can't see shit.
比格斯死了 克里斯
Biggles is gone, Chris.
昨天手术... 他死在手术台上了
He was in surgery yesterday, and... he died on that table.
我是塔雅 现在不方便接电话 请留言
Hey, this is Taya. I can't get to the phone, so please leave a message.
是我... 就是想听听你的声音
It's me... Just calling to hear your voice.
我想你们 我也想了你说的那些话
I'm missing you guys. Been thinking about some things you said.
告诉孩子们我爱他们 我也爱你
Tell the kids I love 'em. I love you, too.
别捡
Don't pick it up.
别他妈捡起来
Don't you fucking pick it up.
真他妈该死
Son of a bitch.
赶紧扔了
Fucking drop it.
小傻瓜 你赶紧给我扔了
Drop it, you little cocksucker.
听好了 上头坚信如果能把基地的残兵堵在丁字墙这里
All right, listen up. The head-shed believe this T-wall here will help win the war
战争就快结束了
by trapping remaining AQI behind it.
问题是墙后很深的地方能藏一个狙击手
Problem is the engineers building the goddamn things
这鬼地方完全暴漏在他的枪口下
are getting picked off by one single sniper from deep behind the wall.
能藏多深?
How deep?
- 大概一千米  - 是穆斯塔法?
- Roughly 1,000 meters.  - Is it Mustafa?
- 穆什么?  - 我也不知道
- Mu-who?  - I don't know, dude.
就是那个杀了我们朋友比格斯的狙击手
The sniper who killed our fucking friend Biggles, man.
你们想他是谁就是谁 我只要他死
He can be whoever the fuck you need him to be. We just need him dead.
我们会把你们运到距离敌人六个街区的位置
We'll shuttle you six blocks north into enemy territory,
他开枪时 你们就在他鼻子底下
which will put you right up under the sniper's nose when he takes his shot, okay?
- 在沙尘暴中心?  - 把你的护目镜带上 斑比
- In the middle of a fucking sandstorm?  - Bring your fucking goggles, Bambi.
我们必须干掉他 明白吗? 去准备吧
We need to shut this shooter down. Understood? Gear up.
- 是 长官  - 是 长官
- Yes, sir.  - Yes, sir.
安全 出发
It's clear. Move out.
安全
Clear.
- 我们负责警戒 你负责狙击  - 明白
- We're maneuver. You're base.  - Yep.
走
Go.
走!
Go!
- 安全  - 前进
- Clear.  - Moving.
往前! 走!
Go! Go!
一切安全
All clear.
设置警戒
Set security.
街上有动静 别开火
The streets are crawling. Hold your fire.
欢迎变成沙人
Enter the fucking sandman.
- 有人受伤!  - 全体退后!
- Man down!  - Man back!
操!
Shit!
枪声是从东边来的!
Shot came from the east!
我们搞错方向了
We set up in the wrong fucking direction.
不管他 别开枪 这些敌人就在下面
Doesn't matter. Hold your fire. We got uglies right below us.
有异常 距离1900码
I got something 1,900 yards out.
操 那么远你看都看不见 别开枪 你会暴露我们
Fuck, you can't even see that far out. Hold your fire. You'll expose us all.
他说得对 传奇 不好
He's right, Legend. No bueno.
更正 是2100码
Correction. It's 2,100 yards out.
那可是一英里之外了 不可能打中的 克里斯
That's more than a mile. Impossible shot, Chris.
就是他
It's him.
我是捣碎机小组 我看到目标了 请求出动快速反应部队 结束
This is task unit bruiser. I got eyes on target. Initiate QRF. Over.
收到 快速反应部队20分钟后到
Copy that. ET on quick reaction force is 20 minutes out.
- 他能看见我们的人  - 你能确认是他吗?
- He has eyes on our guys.  - Can you confirm it's him?
肯定是
It's him.
- 就是他  - 听你的了 克里斯
- Oh, it's him.  - It's your call, Chris.
快速反应部队20分钟就到 你别他妈开枪!
Quick reaction force is 20 minutes out. You'll stand the fuck down!
有信心就干吧
If you got it, take it, man.
瞄准物小 失误也小
Aim small, miss small.
为了比格斯 干吧
Do it for Biggles.
传奇 你把我们坑惨了
You just fucked us, Legend.
目标被击毙
Tango down.
我们急需快速反应部队!
We need QRF asap!
任务完成
Mission accomplished.
他盯上我们的人了
He had eyes on our guys.
- 所以我把他击毙了  - 是啊 我们现在彻底完蛋了
- And I took him out.  - Yeah. Now we're fucked like a football bat.
比格斯会很骄傲的
Biggles would be proud.
你做到了 克里斯
You did it, Chris.
E7K 请注意 有敌人从各个方向向你们的位置接近
Echo 7 kilo, be advised you have enemy approaching all directions of your pos.
看着点东边! 操你妈的 传奇 操!
White-side! Goddamn it, Legend. Fuck!
好吧 我们走 来吧
Yeah, let's go. Come on.
听着 上楼有两条路 我们要把两个楼梯全部堵住
All right, I see two ways up onto the roof. We wanna lock both staircases.
保留子弹
Conserve ammo.
来吧 操你妈的
Get some, motherfuckers.
E7K 请注意 在你们的西边有敌人的重机枪
Echo 7 kilo, you have tango-heavy gun on your green-side.
我们遭遇敌方火力 东边! 有敌方火力 东边!
We're taking effective fire, white-side! Effective fire, white-side!
- D 我只剩下两个弹夹了! 我们得走了!  - 哥们 别他妈停止射击啊!
- "D", I'm down to two mags! We gotta move!  - Don't stop fucking shooting, man!
快速反应部队被堵在在三个街区外了
QRF's stuck three blocks out.
- 我没子弹了  - 三点钟方向 最后一个弹夹
- I'm out!  - 3 o'clock. Loading last mag.
我只有一个弹夹了!
I've only got one mag left!
我没子弹了! 我没子弹了! 谁有子弹?!
I'm black! I'm black! Anybody got a mag?!
我们支持不下去了! 我们得走了!
We can't hold 'em any longer! We gotta move!
那些人只能等死了
Those guys are sitting ducks.
- 我可不想被拖到大街上  - 就是这样 干吧
- I don't wanna get dragged in the street.  - That's it. Do it.
叫人吧
Call it in.
我是R2B 请求空中火力支援
This is Rio 2 Bravo requesting ordnance drop.
- 坐标04837959  - 目标是你们的位置
- Grid number 04837959.  - That target location is your position.
我当然他妈的知道我的位置! 他们就在我们上面! 投放就好!
I know my fucking position! They're right on top of us. Just drop it!
V34 向最后的攻击地点前进
Viper 34, move to final attack heading.
我是V34 收到 还有30秒
Viper 34. Roger. 30 seconds out.
喂?
Hello?
宝贝?
Baby?
克里斯? 宝贝 我... 宝贝 我听不到 喂?
Chris? Baby, I ca... baby, I can't hear you. Hello?
我准备好了
I'm ready.
- 我准备好回家了  - 什么?
- I'm ready to come home.  - What?
我看到那栋建筑物了
I have the building in sight.
出什么事了?
What's happening?
我准备好回家了 宝贝
I'm ready to come home, baby.
克里斯?
Chris?
这里空气不太好 我支持不了多久了
It's pretty bad air up here. I can't hold this much longer.
让那个飞行员发射吧
Tell the pilot "turn it loose."
V34 发射
Viper 34. Fire away.
未击中目标
Target missed.
操
Shit.
我们现在就得走了! 走吧! 我们走!
We need to exit now! Let's go! Let's move!
我们得走了!
We gotta move!
E7K 可以从西边离开
Echo 7 kilo, green-side is clear for exit.
我看着外面 听着我的口令 冲向西边的电线杆!
I got the out. Green-side pole on my go!
他们在屋顶上
They're on the roof.
我们走!
Let's go!
最后一个人!
Last man!
到后面来!
Get to the back!
走! 走! 走!
Go! Go! Go!
快来! 里面来 里面来!
Come on! Inside, inside!
到车子里来! 到车子里来! 我们得走了!
Get in the truck! Get in the truck now! We got to go!
来吧! 我们得走了!
Come on! We got to get out now!
把我拉上来
Let me up.
快点 把我拉上来 快点
Come on, let me up. Come on.
克里斯在哪里?
Where's Chris?
他刚刚还在我后面呢 克里斯呢?
He was just behind me. Where is Chris, man?
他妈的把门打开
Open the fucking door.
快他妈停车!
Stop the goddamn rig!
他在哪?! 克里斯!
Where is he?! Chris!
克里斯 快来!
Chris, come on!
- 快来!  - 他妈的停车啊 哥们!
- Come on!  - Hold the fucking vehicle, man!
我们不会离开你的! 来吧 克里斯! 抓住我的手! 快上来 克里斯!
We can't leave you! Come on, Chris! Grab my hand! Come on, Chris!
把他拉进来!
Pull him in now!
来吧 克里斯!
Come on, Chris!
- 嗯?  - 嘿 是我
- Yeah?  - Hey, it's me.
我... 我收到消息说你在飞机上什么的
I just... I got this weird message that you were on a plane or something?
是啊 是啊 我提早出来了
Yeah. Yeah, I got out early.
是吗?
You did?
那你现在在德国 还是... 你在哪?
So, what, are you in Germany, or... where?
不 我在这里 我...
No, I'm here. I'm...
我在国内
I'm stateside.
你回家了?
You're home?
你... 你在干什么?
What... what are you doing?
我想我还需要一点时间
I guess I just needed a minute.
克里斯 孩... 孩子们都很想见你 已经九个月了
Chris, the... the kids are dying to see you. It's been nine months.
我要回家了
I'm coming home.
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
嗯 我很好
Yeah, I'm good.
宝贝 回家好吗?
Babe, come home. Okay?
其实 我们... 我们很想你
You know, we... we miss you.
好的
Okay.
嘿 克里斯?
Hey, Chris?
宝贝
Babe.
宝贝 我... 我出去了
Hon, I'm... I'm going outside.
- 好的  - 高点
- Get it.  - Higher.
看看你 我又能见到你的脸了 宝贝 样子不错
Look at you. I can see your face again, babe. Looks good.
- 好的  - 看上去不一样了
- Oh, good.  - Looks different.
比赛是这个礼拜六
So the game's this Saturday.
他是队里最高的孩子 医生说他能长到六尺四
You know, he's the tallest kid on the team. Doctor said he could be 6'4".
真是疯了 对吧?
Isn't that insane?
我等不及让你看他比赛了 不过当其他小孩跳到他身上的时候
I can't wait for you to see him play. I go so crazy, though,
我都会疯掉 我需要你在那里 安抚我
when the other kids jump on him. Like, I need you there as, like, a leveler,
你懂吗?
you know what I mean?
嘿 也许你还可以当教练呢?
Hey, maybe you could even coach, you know?
肯娜快要掉牙了 我真怕她会把那颗牙吞下去
'Kenna's gonna lose that tooth, and I'm so worried she's gonna swallow it,
比如在她睡觉的时候什么的 她说她只允许你来拔它
like, in her sleep or something. And she said she'd let you pull it, but only you.
你行吗?
Would you do that?
克里斯!
Chris!
我接到了个很有趣的电话 是你的妻子打来的
I got a very interesting phone call. It's from your wife.
她和我说了烧烤的时候发生的事了
She told me about the barbecue.
是啊 那事不太好
Yeah, that was unfortunate. Yeah.
事情似乎有点失控了
Things seem like they got a little out of hand.
- 你担心吗?  - 不担心 先生
- Are you worried?  - No, sir.
你不担心那天发生的事 也不担心可能发生的事?
So you're not worried about what happened, or what might happen?
不担心 先生 我不担心
No, sir, I'm not worried about that.
让我问你一个问题 克里斯
Let me ask you a question, Chris.
你在战场上待了多少时间?
How much time did you spend in-country?
- 呃 四次部署 所以...  - 差不多有一千天?
- Well, four tours, so...  - That's like, what, 1,000 days?
是啊 差不多
Yeah, sounds about right.
如果我告诉你 海军说你
Would you be surprised if I told you
杀了160个人 你会吃惊吗?
that the Navy has credited you with over 160 kills?
你有没有想过...
Do you ever think that...
你可能见过 或者做过一些让你后悔的事?
you might have seen things or done some things over there that you wish you hadn't?
我不会这样的 不会
Oh, that's not me. No.
- 不会怎么样?  - 我只是在保护我的人
- What's not you?  - I was just protecting my guys.
他们想杀我们的士兵 但是...
They were trying to kill our soldiers, and...
我见到我的造物主的时候 我愿意面对我开的每一枪
I'm willing to meet my creator and answer for every shot that I took.
我不能...
The thing that...
我不能释怀的是那些我没能救的人
haunts me are all the guys that I couldn't save.
其实 我愿意也可以在那里 但是我不在那里 我在这里 我放弃了
You know, I'm willing and able to be there, but I'm not. I'm here. I quit.
所以你希望能救更多的人?
So you wish you could've saved more guys?
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
其实 你可以在这个医院的走廊里走走
You know, you can walk down any hall in this hospital.
这里有很多需要拯救的士兵
We got plenty of soldiers need saving.
想走一走吗?
Wanna take a walk?
当然
Sure.
好吧 我要给你看一个东西
All right. I wanna show you something.
我还在抽烟
I still smoke.
我生不了什么气 因为抽烟救了我的右手
Can't be too mad at it 'cause it kinda saved my right hand.
为什么?
How so?
我被炸的时候 我的两只手都在方向盘下面
When I got blown up, I had both of my hands on the bottom of the steering wheel.
在炮弹爆炸之前 我把我的手松开了
And right before the explosion went off, I took my hand off,
拿了一根香烟 放在我手里
grabbed a cigarette, stuck it in my mouth.
我点烟的时候 炸弹爆炸了
And when I went to go light it, the explosion happened.
它把整个方向盘和我的左手都炸掉了
And it took the whole bottom of the steering wheel and my left hand off.
我这样特别幸运 它还是把我的右手毁了 但是...
And I was lucky that I had this. I mean, it still fucked up my right hand, but...
- 是啊  - 它还在
- Yeah.  - I still got it.
- 你还抽烟吗?  - 是啊 我还抽烟
- And you still smoke?  - Yeah, I still smoke.
没打中 往右三英尺 拜托 维恩 你能干得更好的
Miss. Three inches to the right. Come on, Wynn. You can do better than that.
把这个往右边偏一点
Bring this to the right.
你两只眼睛都要张开 你会很惊讶扳机的作用
Make sure you keep both eyes open. Let that trigger surprise you.
我们不是在打坏人 我们在打纸
We're not shooting bad guys. We're shooting paper.
你这个传奇能不能不要给我搞破坏?
How about The Legend stops trying to fuck up my shot?
- 行不行?  - 那你能不能打中一次?
- How about that?  - How about you hit one?
- 击中!  - 就这样
- Hit!  - There you go.
爽啊 哥们 感觉就像我的蛋蛋回来了
Bull's eye, boy. Damn, if that don't feel like I got my balls back.
你为什么要和我们待在一起?
Why you spending all this time with us, man?
我知道你有家庭
I know you got a family.
我听说你在去打仗之前收集了很多鞋子?
I heard you had a boot collection before the war?
所以我在想 我们好像尺寸差不多
So I was thinking, I saw we were about the same size.
说真的 哥们 你为什么要这样?
Seriously, man. Why do you do it?
我们互相照顾 对吧?
Well, we take care of each other, right?
看看你能不能连续打中两次
Let's see if you can't hit two in a row.
来吧 哥们 你能做到的
Come on, man. You got this.
- 击中!  - 太棒了
- Hit!  - Nice.
- 击中!  -
- Hit!  - Goddamn.
现在谁是传奇?
Who's the legend now?
你不会喜欢这个称号的 相信我
That's a title you don't want. Trust me.
嘿 你能不能跳下来? 我会把它们递给你
Yo, will you hop down? I'll give 'em to you.
- 你想再拿一个吗?  - 好啊
- You add one more?  - Yeah.
- 好吧 把它们搬进去  - 好的
- All right, take 'em inside.  - All right.
过来
Come here.
这里的生活也不差 对吧?
It's not a bad life out here, is it?
让他都笑起来了
Got a smile on his face.
我看他挺开心的
Looks cheery to me.
做他爱做的事
Just doing his thing.
和他挥手告别吧
Wave goodbye to him.
哦! 操 谁干的?!
Oh! Fuck, who is that?!
- 哦! 宝贝 是你吗?  - 是啊哈哈!
- Oh! Babe, is that you?  - Yep-A-Doo-Dee!
- 宝贝 我他妈受伤了 卧槽  - 怎么了?
- Baby, I fucking hurt myself. Shit.  - What?
没事 我没事 我没事! 我没事 操
No, I'm all right. I'm all right! I'm all right. Fuck.
- 宝贝 对不起  - 没事
- Baby, I'm sorry.  - It's okay.
出了什么事? 别...
What happened? Don't...
让一颗心脏停止跳动这事真的很大
You know that it's a heck of a thing to stop a beating heart.
是啊
Yeah.
所以你的第一次我们要一起做
That's why we're gonna do it together for your first time.
好的
All right.
记住 你要冷静...
Now, remember, you gotta be calm...
自信...
confident...
不要犹豫
and you never hesitate.
- 好的  - 听懂了吗 兄弟?
- All right.  - You got it, bubba?
- 听懂了  - 感觉不错吧?
- I got it.  - You feel good?
是啊
Yeah.
2013年 2月2日
举起手来 小姐
Hands in the air, little lady.
举起手来
Hands in the air.
现在 你把手放下
Now, you drop them drawers.
慢点放下
But you drop 'em nice and easy.
宝贝 看看你自己
Oh, baby, look at you.
- 看看你自己  - 看看你自己
- Look at you.  - Look at you.
我能和你说一件事吗?
Can I tell you something?
- 和法官说吧  - 别闹
- Tell it to the judge.  - Stop it.
不 我真的为你感到骄傲 我怎么说都不够
No. I am so proud of you, and I don't tell you enough.
我为你骄傲 你真是个好爸爸
I'm so proud of you. And you're such a great father.
我的丈夫回来了我真的很开心
And I am so happy that I've got my husband back.
我也知道你为了到这里来有多努力
And I also know how hard you fought to get here.
你值得我为你努力
You're worth fighting for.
现在再和我说一件事 你... 给这条牛仔裤打褶皱了?
Now tell me one other thing. Did you... did you pleat those jeans?
是的 女士 我想它们应该就在下面
Yes, ma'am. I believe they're right down the middle.
哦 你现在就是个普通的老牛仔了
Oh, you're just a regular old cowboy again.
是的 那你现在... 现在要不真的把它们放下?
That's right. Now, why don't you... why don't you really drop them drawers?
我没穿啊 宝贝
I'm not wearing any drawers, baby.
我有四分钟
I got four minutes.
只需要四分钟吗?
Is that all it takes?
不 只需要两分钟 然后我还需要两分钟来看着你
No, it takes two minutes. But then again I want two minutes to look at you.
你不去农场吗?
Aren't you going to the range?
你要带谁出去?
Who are you taking out?
一个海军陆战队的 他妈妈一直求我
This marine. His mama kept asking me.
她把车子停在小学外面 然后她说"你能帮帮我的儿子吗?"
She parks cars at the elementary school, and she said, "can you help out my son?"
我就想... 我只能今天去 所以...
And I just thought... today's the only day I can really do it, so...
只需要下午一点点时间 我会回来的
It's gonna be just a little bit of the afternoon. I'll be back.
太棒了!
Yes!
- 你得留着内裤...  - 爸爸
- You make sure you keep them drawers...  - Daddy.
- 怎么了? 怎么了?  - 爸爸 你想玩小龙斯派罗的大冒险吗?
- What's up? What's up?  - Dad, you wanna play Skylanders?
不 我现在没法玩 我回来再玩 儿子
No, I can't play right now. I'll do it when I get back, boy.
但是你现在是8级 那可不行
But, see, you're on level 8, and that doesn't work.
我才4级 我可不想... 我想赢啊 你得让我赢啊
I gotta be on level 4. And I don't want... I wanna win. You gotta let me win.
不可能!
No way!
- 戳熊!  - 戳啥?
- Poke the bear!  - Poke the what?
- Poke the bear! - Poke the what?!
戳熊!
Poke the bear!
不是的! 你得咆哮 就像...
No! You're supposed to roar, like...
像什么? 像野兽是吗? 像什么?
Like what? Like a beast, right? Like what?
好吧 兄弟 你照顾好我妻女好吗?
All right, bubba. Y'all look after our women, okay?
- 好的  - 好的 这是个很大的责任
- Yeah.  - Okay. It's a big responsibility.
你能做到吗?
You up for it?
好的 一会儿见 宝贝
All right. See you later, baby.
- 我爱你  - 我也爱你
- I love you.  - I love you back.
- 你怎么样? 过得好吗?  - 挺好的
- How are you? You good?  - Good.
我们去开两个小时的车 开几枪
We're gonna go about a two-hour drive and shoot some guns
然后路上可以聊聊天 怎么样?
and maybe have a little conversation along the way. What you say?
- 好的  - 好的 我们走
- Yeah.  - All right. Let's go.
- 谢谢  - 好的
- Thank you.  - Yep.
嘿 你吃了吗? 你饿吗? 你想路上吃点东西吗?
Hey, you eat yet? You hungry? You wanna get something on the way?
克里斯・凯尔在那一天被他帮助的一个退役老兵杀害